Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chats.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys.
Krish NAik: Thanks for the confirmation. Morning, everyone. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Today, a little bit about the codebase that we'll be discussing. So, last week, like, Saturday and Sunday, both the days we have gone through the
Krish NAik: deployment phase, okay, and finally, we'll be talking about, the codebase today. So, little bit boring, but a few interesting things are there that I'll be focusing on today. And then I think, from tomorrow, we can start with Langra.
Krish NAik: Little bit about, agents, orchestration…
Krish NAik: And finally, we will move on with our fifth project that we have.
Krish NAik: on Agent Epac, okay?
Krish NAik: Any questions, anyone, you can ask me, because today I can't take questions, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Today, we have enough timers.
Krish NAik: You can ask me questions in the chat.
Krish NAik: Anything important is there, I will be… Okay, fine. So let's start with the part with respect to the poor guest.
Krish NAik: I think this is virtual, man, this is what's talk through.
Krish NAik: Alright, what do you think, Gemma 4? Gemma 4 is, good, I will say, for local use, really, like, Gemma 4, I can say that it's cooked as well.
Krish NAik: But again, it depends upon, like, which parameter model that you are using, but I will say that, yes, using it as an SLM really is good.
Krish NAik: 4 billion one I will go with, not with the 2 billion one.
Krish NAik: If I have a lot of knowledge bases, then also I feel that 4 billion one is better as compared to 2. A lot of new things came, like, till 2 to 3 days.
Krish NAik: I think GPT 5.5 got launched.
Krish NAik: Anybody tested it?
Krish NAik: In projects, or anywhere.
Krish NAik: I have not, till now, tested, codex, okay. it is good, okay, yes.
Krish NAik: Because, actually.
Krish NAik: lesser use of MCP servers and other things, and even, deepSheq came? Yes, DeepShek V4, like, after…
Krish NAik: I think, V3 came… around.
Krish NAik: 2024 December… okay, not around, I think, after more than one year, DeepSec has released a V4, and V4 is also really good. The number of parameters, they have increased, that's pretty huge, okay? 1.6 trillion parameters.
Krish NAik: So, I will say that,
Krish NAik: The Pro version and the flash version, I'll be testing out the flash version this week.
Krish NAik: Okay, Pro or the flash, flash one that I will be going ahead with. The Pro one is really, like, in my local, it's very hard to test. Probably, if you have seen, like, Krish, got the DGX,
Krish NAik: So, probably, I think, 2 to 3 days, let him test, then I will bring the hardware, and… No.
Krish NAik: And then I will do the testing or not.
Krish NAik: But, foreshadow Pro will be better, but initial testing I want to do with the flash mode.
Krish NAik: I tested Gemma on my Pixel phone, and, Gibbs quite quickly. However, when I run it on my laptop using ULAMA, it's noticeably slower. Is there a specific reason?
Krish NAik: Really, it depends upon on your local, also, if you have a little bit of VRAM, the responses get speed up varage, whereas in every phone or in Pixel, there is a dedicated GP mode, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, Nitesh is asking, ask him to restore, reinstall, it helped.
Krish NAik: Okay, Codex.
Krish NAik: I was… this week, I was even working on auto research part, okay,
Krish NAik: From Kaparti's, report, but really, I can say that is also good.
Krish NAik: Self-recursive improvement on your agent looks.
Krish NAik: But a little bit token-expensive task. It means that, you need a lot of tokens.
Krish NAik: Because I spent, my tokens got exhausted after 5 to 6 hours. I was using with, Sonnet 4.6, the 1 million context window.
Krish NAik: But again, I think that that is going to be really game-changing.
Krish NAik: Auto research part that I have tested.
Krish NAik: better than, like, self-improving with respect to everything. It can be your skills, it can be your code base, it can be with respect to your… any type of metrics, retrieval. For example, like, a simple example, like, I was testing, it was with respect to chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, what will be the optimal, chunk size based on the document input? And really, I will say that, yes, it works good with the self-improvement loops.
Krish NAik: But again, and I can say that in the last, week, last 7 days, the pricing of tokens has really increased.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I can say Claude is also testing that on their $20 plan, they will be removing Cloud code access. Initially, they have done the testing with only 2% of their signups.
Krish NAik: Codex, again, really costly. GLM has increased their price 2X.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, getting access to a lot of tokens, I can say. For your initial testing, the cheapest one
Krish NAik: I can say that, from that, ByteDance family, they have launched their new coding plan. That is the cheapest right now. I feel that after one month, even that will be expensive. So that's why they are not giving yearly subscriptions, only quarterly subscriptions that they have.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I feel that in the next 6 months, the price of tokens will be pretty much high, due to the demand with respect to hardwares.
Krish NAik: That is also… Little bit scarce, I can see.
Krish NAik: Aniroth is asking, please change what changes. In their $20 plan, the new sign-ups, it means that you have to take the minimum $100 plan, then only you will get access to Cloud Code. Previously, like, in $20 plan also, they were providing.
Krish NAik: They are initially testing it with only 2% of the user signups, but I feel that, that change will be upcoming, at least in the next 60 days or 90 days, you might see that shift, because the price of tokens is getting higher and better.
Krish NAik: with, respect to… just because, think about if you are actually working… there's a real reason behind that, because everybody is working on self-improvement loops, and for any type of LLMs you are working with, the token consumption is really, really high.
Krish NAik: It's very, very high.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that you will be spending close to, like, for a single experiment, like, if you're doing, it depends upon the total number of experiments. If you're at least doing 50 experiments also, then the token consumption can be close to 20 million to 30 million, easily. So that's why the pricing…
Krish NAik: For open source models like GLM, Deep6, so if you're not having a hardware, it becomes really a problem, as compared to paying for the API, because the costs
Krish NAik: I have seen that everywhere, Reddit, Twitter, everybody is telling about that, pricing is cool.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, can you share the, GitLo of that OctodeClassification group? I was working on that, I've not pushed that into my GitHub, but you can look into Andres Kaparte's skills. I think that was by Francesca Avsky.
Krish NAik: Sampath, how do you choose LLM in terms of any metrics or parameters? It depends upon whether I'm working based on knowledge bases or not. Really, if you are working with respect to knowledge bases, you really don't need a very good LLM.
Krish NAik: I can say that anything between open source models, you can pick that 8 billion to 24 billion model.
Krish NAik: And at least you should have 32GB in your system. At least, because in Macs you have a unified memory, okay, or in Windows or Linux-based systems, at least you have that. It is good to do.
Krish NAik: I tried the auto-research loop around, 30 million, tokens of GLM coding plan, yes, the same month.
Krish NAik: the GLM coding land, right now, it increased a lot. Even I took a quarterly plan, even I will be upgrading to the new 5 to 1.
Krish NAik: From that Pythons Academy. That is the cheapest right now in the market.
Krish NAik: And, at least you guys can try, because the NVIDIA build, I already showed you the NVIDIA APIs also. So, from there, also, you'll be getting free access to tokens, at least I can say.
Krish NAik: It's also fast, I have done the testing initially 2 to 3 days, that is completely free. So, yes, there is a limitation, I think, till 10,000 credits or something like that, but yes, you guys can use it first.
Krish NAik: I know the basics of Gen AI, genetic, Krishnak, bundles, but it totally depends, like, I know the basics.
Krish NAik: P6 is fine, but again, BASIC doesn't, Projects part, really.
Krish NAik: there are so many projects you can have a look. If it is relevant to you, then only take it. Otherwise, not. Because one project that I have actually given the task to one of the
Krish NAik: mentors are working on a scalable rack pipeline. That is really… I think it might take him 2 to 3 weeks for… to do the recording, but once that project comes, even I'll be sharing the record in your project, because that is really a very, very big project.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: Increased… increased or decreased? SK increased, increased. Every pudding plant, because only the bite one, I felt that that is the cheapest one in the market, if somebody is looking.
Krish NAik: Mcp servers, I will be using it in the fifth project.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm gonna send a new bus.
Krish NAik: Even MCP servers, okay, fine, because with the launch of Codex 5.5, MCP servers are pretty much
Krish NAik: Not in English.
Krish NAik: Okay, they are trying to remove. So recently, I can see that people are getting diverted.
Krish NAik: towards much more function-based calls rather than MCP, but again, it totally depends upon your use case.
Krish NAik: We were talking about MCB in the final project.
Krish NAik: I've started working, I'm actually reducing a few things, the complexity of the web project. There were a lot of containers, I've taken landfuse this time.
Krish NAik: For your catching, yes, Redis is there. This time, a little bit different approach, rather than direct chunking, I'm keeping the chunks in Postgres, from PoolScrease that I'm bringing it
Krish NAik: Through your docklings, and that way, a little bit structural changes.
Krish NAik: So, you can have a look at the Agentic rack project in the GitHub.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Chaitan, will you be covering as part of the next project? Sorry, I missed a few sessions, especially the…
Krish NAik: Custom rubrics, custom rubrics, what are the things that you are defining? Golden dataset Examples.
Krish NAik: I'll be keeping it in, like, Project 5.
Krish NAik: Can you, make your DJX for Apple Maps as a network design, as an LLM model? Yes, I can make it, but dedicatedly, I use my, like, Apple, so I'm making that. Whereas the DJX part, yes, through an SSH, I can access it in my… that's the idea to do the setup.
Krish NAik: Yes, Forrest Chang. Exactly correct, Matesh.
Krish NAik: Okay, the Forrest Chang is the main guy who has taken the implementation, because Andri Kapajo didn't publish any, directly. He posted a tweet that tweet got, I think. I saw last time it was close to 8 million views.
Krish NAik: So, based on that tweet, here's done the implementation, so you can actually have a look. That's really good, but always remember the token consumption is really, really.
Krish NAik: So, start with, lesser number of experiments, keep it, like, every experiment should be under, like, 5 minutes or 7 minutes, and maximum go for, initially, like, 15 to 20 experiments, so across that.
Krish NAik: Let's about…
Krish NAik: No, Gardress is there in Project Y, okay?
Krish NAik: Gardress is there, because a few repos that I have updated, let me just, bring that.
Krish NAik: I can rule this is a long one.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is a project I have, started working, but again, a few things are there. This time, I have used dedicatedly open search.
Krish NAik: Okay, for the embedding, dashboard, a lot of things are there. I've started working a little bit, making it more easier to teach, because really working with a lot of containers, it becomes harder for me, takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I'll be… this time, I really don't want to work with ULAMA or VLLM, because in Project 4, I've already shown you how to use it within a Docker environment, so that part, I'll be skipping it, and I'll be using the plain OpenAI version.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, with respect to the, security base, so this is also why I've kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if you want, really, with respect to all the different type of test things, input validation, hardening, prompt, okay, token budget models, so this part also you can have a look if you really want to have a check on security-based pipelines.
Krish NAik: I've kept few more things I'll be adding on the post-processing of security features.
Krish NAik: All right, so I think we can start our initial session. So, let's start.
Krish NAik: Purchasing, sir, do you suggest purchasing the $20
Krish NAik: I don't suggest, Claude, like, what is the main purpose? If you are using it in production, it's better, codex or Claude. For your initial testing, you really don't need such a costlier, plan, because in $20 plan, the limits are very, very… you will be exhausted.
Krish NAik: Like, you cannot sit at least for 2-3 hours, so Anirud, not worth it.
Krish NAik: In that case, I think that, white, this is the latest one, I think, none.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the new, model coding PAM. Okay, so I… I think I'll be getting it today or tomorrow, I've been testing it with, because GLM 5.1 access that I need, and this is right now the cheapest one in the market. If I go with the quarterly, then also, like, it's pretty much cheaper as compared to the GLM plans.
Krish NAik: JLM plans, a lot of people are asking in the chat, really, they have increased their…
Krish NAik: I can say, plan a lot, okay? Like, in December, when I purchased it, it was around,
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see this is 1536 green, like…
Krish NAik: In December, this was $288 per year. They increased it to 360 per year, then $760, and right now it's $15.36. So I feel the pricing of the tokens is getting pricier.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… right now, the cheapest one here, also, like, $14 per month. Again, I feel that
Krish NAik: At least this is cheaper as compared to that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I was telling about that. I'm sharing the referral link also if you really want to have a look.
Krish NAik: UK.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: GLM, I'm not sharing because it's very, very costly.
Krish NAik: But again, because I've been using the Pro plan much more as compared to the Max plan, it does the job, because I'm already a CloudCloud user, CloudX user, so I just keep it for testing with my open boot.
Krish NAik: Okay, a few people are asking for this one also I'll share.
Krish NAik: Alibaba has also a plan. I feel that that is also good, $50 plan. But again, it totally depends upon the usage. Are you a Peru user or not? It means that every day, are you spending, like.
Krish NAik: 5 to 6 hours.
Krish NAik: on, that.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can integrate this with plot code anytime. That's easier. You just have to change the base URL. Okay, so you can see plot code, client.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, and this week, even I have been testing the Hermes agent this month. Anybody has tested Hermus?
Krish NAik: That is also really, really good. Better than OpenClure. Much, much better than OpenClure. I was, doing the testing with, headless browsers this time, Hartwell, because this project, again, because you know right now.
Krish NAik: every, two to three months, something comes up, the Hermes, Agent, I think.
Krish NAik: I'm not a researcher.
Krish NAik: Okay, because here the number of stars increased, so I thought about… when I last saw it was around 100K, but, this is also why I'm feeling that, much better, it's really good, you can test it out.
Krish NAik: If you have any… a dedicated… like, I do have a hosting that,
Krish NAik: I can say VPS, which means I was doing the testing there, and I will say that this is also a good project, better than OpenDraw. It has really impressed me.
Krish NAik: Okay, a lot of self-improvements are there, auto-healing is there.
Krish NAik: support, so this is also a good one. In the next, I think, cohort, I'll be adding Hermos.
Krish NAik: Then, hardness engineering, because the shift has been from prompt engineering to context engineering, now it's pretty much hardness engineering.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, new things with respect to that, I will be adding it, but really, like, this one I'll be discussing in the next one, but really, I felt like this is also really good. If you have time, please do check it out.
Krish NAik: so many updates that come, guys, like, how many links I will share.
Krish NAik: So you have to be a little bit active, and… Hmm…
Krish NAik: Edge LLMs, although I am planning to add it in the next cohort.
Krish NAik: Edge LLMs, I feel that, yes, it is important right now, running on your mobile devices.
Krish NAik: That is not only.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's start with our core discussion today.
Krish NAik: How do you get that update? Everywhere. Check the updates. LinkedIn, everybody is posting, that's why, Mates.
Krish NAik: Chaitan, were we created any prompt or agent? No, no, no, no, everywhere. Like, I spent a case, 30 minutes on LinkedIn, Twitter.
Krish NAik: These are the best places.
Krish NAik: Alright, Matesh, do you have any agent request, site information and admin by mail?
Krish NAik: I don't have anything such like that. I spend time manually.
Krish NAik: My major three sources are Substack, Twitter, X, basically. Okay, and, LinkedIn, and Reddit. These are the four things that I would much…
Krish NAik: Because every good author is there in Substack, so it's easier.
Krish NAik: PayPal have shifted from Medium to Substack a lot.
Krish NAik: And do check out, majorly, the Twitter, I can also say, right now, I feel the community is really active.
Krish NAik: The response in Twitter is better as compared to LinkedIn.
Krish NAik: That is rather for yarnat.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's start with our, board-based discussion.
Krish NAik: Okay, so already we have done it, so today, just a high-level overview, exactly what are the things.
Krish NAik: And what are the new things still now in this, cohort that we have not gone through? Okay, that, path I'll be, telling you in detail.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think…
Krish NAik: So, let's start with our code page discussion. Everyone, you can switch on to your repo. Okay, so right now, even I'm in the core branch, the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: Okay, and okay, the dot dot hidden folder is not important.
Krish NAik: Okay, the front-end folder… so… in this particular folder, I was having the React frontend, but again, I have not discussed, neither shown you, so leave this part not important for you. This I have actually white-coated, so… not required.
Krish NAik: Now, docs folder already shared with you notebooks. Again, I have not worked on any notebooks there, rather than… Ulama folder. Now, ULAMA folder, how many of you remember? What is the purpose of the ULAMA folder? Anybody remember, this is the first thing that I have shown you in the first session of Project 4.
Krish NAik: what I was executing in the Olama folder. Any way to remember.
Krish NAik: two things were there. One is running your JLM OCR.
Krish NAik: locally in Ollama, and from there, you will be, getting the results, okay? So, like, I'm just showing you. So, first of all, you'll be getting the results in the format of JSON, and then we're doing the visualization part. Okay, so simply, like, this is the test part script that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, the idea is to load up your GLM OCR model, and from there, get the results in JSON. Okay, so this is basically the docklink report.json, where I was capturing everything with respect to the bounding box coordinates for each of the attributes.
Krish NAik: Polygon-based, coordinates, The content, what type of label.
Krish NAik: So you can see, like, document title is coming. So for everything, as I have shown you, like, GLM OCR is really good in that.
Krish NAik: It's, lightweight, it is having the Ollama support, but yeah, other OCRs also can do the same thing. If you have tested out Chandra, Red Note, okay, Quanfrain, pretty much the same stuff, I can say.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, from your output folder, now, this was the visualize.py, now this is basically a Streamlit application that I have used it, just to, render everything with respect to
Krish NAik: the bounding boxes, because in your JSON file, you have the bounding boxes, but the idea was to do that rendering part, so that you can do the visualization.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the first step is the layout detection with your ppdoc layout v3 version, and finally the OCR part with respect to Ulama. But the main purpose of Visualize was to do the rendering of the
Krish NAik: bounding box coordinates that you have. So, very specifically here, based on the multi-attributes that I have from PPDocLayout, like text, table, formula, algorithm, okay, and these are text-based information that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, I have kept it. So, different colors for different type of bounding boxes. Okay, and finally, I've been using, and a default color, the fallback color that I have kept it. Through that, I'm just rendering the bounding boxes there. Now, this is not part of your core Fast API application.
Krish NAik: Now, if you really look into now, this is the core function. Whenever you get the bounding box.
Krish NAik: So draw bounding boxes on top of each of the objects.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now this is the part. So I think everybody knows how to convert the numbers into mounting boxes.
Krish NAik: Yes, if you have XYWH, XY stands for your What?
Krish NAik: In a bounding box, what does X and Y stand for?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me in the chat, guys.
Krish NAik: not coordinates, don't tell me coordinates. I know that is coordinates, but X and Y, what is the exact position of X and Y in a bounding box?
Krish NAik: Pixel position, no Mitesh Abhishek from, top.
Krish NAik: No X.
Krish NAik: X and Y is not width and height. W and H is your width and height, guys.
Krish NAik: Always, remember, like, generally the computer vision, coordinate system, okay, it starts always from the, top, left corner. That is always… has been the case, okay? So, computer vision, it always works in that way.
Krish NAik: So, it totally depends upon the type of algorithm. So, generally, YOLO-based models, they can sometimes be from the bottom right corner also, or the top left corner. Major, I can say the models are from the top left corner.
Krish NAik: That becomes your X and Y. From there, you have W and H. If you have the W and H value, so simply, you can, actually draw the rectangular, or basically the bounding box coordinator.
Krish NAik: So, let me just give you, because this is the same implementation, and finally, the scaling that I have done, it is the normalization as per the image part. So, let me just, tell you that little bit about the coordinate system.
Krish NAik: Because, why it is important, I'm telling you about the coordinate system, because when you will be doing the, rendering part, it means that if you have the bounding box coordinates, what you can do?
Krish NAik: Can I say that if you have that information, you can get the base64 value, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Quickly tell me, guys.
Krish NAik: So, just wait, let me start, shitty?
Krish NAik: Because that is the main thing, then I can actually pass it to two things.
Krish NAik: I think, iPad via Blueto just to it.
Krish NAik: I verified yet, please.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Let's take, a sample for database system.
Krish NAik: like, X… Why?
Krish NAik: W and H.
Krish NAik: Now, generally, if I'm talking about, X and Y,
Krish NAik: Okay, so sometimes they can be…
Krish NAik: Let's take the start with the midpoint-based system, or the center point of the midpoint.
Krish NAik: And W and H, the width and height.
Krish NAik: Now, let's take the midpoint. So, let's, take a dotted version.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this becomes your X and Y.
Krish NAik: Now, from here, if you have the information, with respect to, let's take height first.
Krish NAik: I got flora Height.
Krish NAik: This becomes your height.
Krish NAik: And this becomes your… let's take the width for me. So, simply, if you have this particular information, you can…
Krish NAik: or draw anything. So, simply to complete the bounding box coordinate.
Krish NAik: The same thing that can be done from here, because the age will also be same.
Krish NAik: Same here also, the width will also be the same.
Krish NAik: Okay, the value of age will also be the same. So that's why it becomes easier for these type of coordinate systems.
Krish NAik: to work on. And majorly, everybody is working on. Now, X and value I have taken as a midpoint. Now, this can be changed
Krish NAik: this point also.
Krish NAik: Because from here, also, you can get the information with respect to H, okay, or if you are treating this one as W, or this one as H, in which available.
Krish NAik: That is also fine. And sometimes from here also, that it can be taken. This one has your W, and this one has your H, right?
Krish NAik: So, that, coordinate system is used by, different, detector systems, whether it's single-stage or, I can say,
Krish NAik: like, dual-stage systems. Like, our CNNs have a different way, and the single-stage, like SSDs and ELO, have a different way.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, what is the benefit of this? If you can actually start working with the
Krish NAik: then I can say that, okay, you can have the let's take… The image corrupt.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can perform an image crop. If you're… can perform an image crop, that particular information can be converted into base64.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this base64 can be sent to two places, or even 3 places. Okay, so what are those 3 places? In a rack-based system, where you can send it?
Krish NAik: One is embedding.
Krish NAik: embedding raw pixels, which we have done it in the Quen. In the quen branch, we have done that, whereas in the deployment branch, we have been used… working with text, so that is not pure multimodal. It's text embedding there. But in the Quen branch, we have worked with pixel-based embeddings.
Krish NAik: Second, where you can send it? What will be the second one?
Krish NAik: Nobody has told it in the chat. Nage is telling embedding vector store multimodal LLM.
Krish NAik: LLM, I will keep it here. LLM.
Krish NAik: In memory, what is the memory moment?
Krish NAik: Cache. No, no, no, no, no. Where I can actually use this base64.
Krish NAik: Embedding means vector store, no.
Krish NAik: This means vector store. Embedding and vector store, same thing. Image captioning, No, guys.
Krish NAik: In the Gwen branch, what are the three things that I have added? You can send it to a read anchor, guys. This I was looking for, the answer.
Krish NAik: Because I used a re-ranker VL model, everybody forgot. I used a dedicated embedding VL model, then came your re-ranker VL model, and then came your LLM with multimodal support.
Krish NAik: So that is an added benefit.
Krish NAik: Okay, and image captioning is fine. It means that image captioning, if you're doing it, it is, really not necessary. Why? Just think about, if you have this base64, you can actually send the original image also, okay, as well as if you want to send the captions, that is also fine.
Krish NAik: Because in the deployment branch also, we can do the same thing, because we have the base64. Image caption is fine, image captions with respect to the original image.
Krish NAik: During your retrieval. In that way, it will know, okay, now, if this is the table, if this is the image. Based on that, you will have the response. So, for sure, the quality of the results will improve, that I have shown it.
Krish NAik: Already. In the mean branch, it is there. In the deployment branch, I'm not sending the B64 to OpenAI, GPT 4.0,
Krish NAik: But in the main branch, I am sending that base 60 code. Okay, and base64, for two things only, I have done it, if you remember.
Krish NAik: One is for your images.
Krish NAik: and for your tables. I have not, done the implementation for algorithms.
Krish NAik: This part, I've not done it, but later on you can improve that. Algorithms, formula.
Krish NAik: And, there was another one, I forgot exactly…
Krish NAik: What was that? But, these two I am sending, actually. Okay, these two I am not actually, creating the base64 and neither saving it in, vector store. But later on, the same implementation can be done for that.
Krish NAik: All right, so, that's why I'm telling you, working with coordinate-based systems, little bit, first time, if you know a little bit about object detection, it's fine. You really don't need to go in-depth, you have to just understand, okay, now this is the return type of a…
Krish NAik: I can say layout detection model. Okay, now from there, if you have this information, later on you can actually reuse it.
Krish NAik: And OCR part comes later. First is the LD part, the layout detection part, guys. Always remember that.
Krish NAik: Because it, first of all, detects whether it's a title, whether it's a paragraph, whether it's a heading, everything. So that is the first step. And if you have the bounding box now, once you have the bounding box, I can say that inside this particular bounding box, apply OC.
Krish NAik: Okay, so inside this, apply OC.
Krish NAik: Inside the BBO. So, OCR part comes in the next phase. Always understand that. A few algorithms, first they do OCR, then LD, the layout detection, but really, I feel that, that should not be the way.
Krish NAik: But, I've seen both the stages, but, major papers are dominating with first LD, and then ACLs.
Krish NAik: All right, now, two things, so those are dual-stage systems that, in this project we have worked with, which is a dual-stage, and I have already given you an example of a single stage.
Krish NAik: Can anybody tell me which model was that, which can perform a single stage?
Krish NAik: I have told you that model.
Krish NAik: And I showed you also the response from the model. In some pages, it was not correct.
Krish NAik: So Ham is close, at least. Okay, Nagash is telling Cold Pali, no, not Cold Pali. Cold Pali-based systems are totally different.
Krish NAik: In Cool Pali, there is nothing concept as, like, bounding box or anything like that. Cool Pali, it will take the entire image and then embedding that.
Krish NAik: Nemo Tron Janika. Correct, you guys are close, it's not Nemo Tron, it's Nemo parts.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Nemo Parse, it was. The Nemo Tron Parse paper.
Krish NAik: That you had.
Krish NAik: That is a single stage. It means that in a single model, both the features are enabled by default, where you can use. But in our project, we have used two different models.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, let's start sharing. Okay, so first of all, I will stop sharing, and let's get back to our codebase discussion.
Krish NAik: Close screen, I think this is such a thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, now comes, drawing bounding boxes. Similarly, polygons in polygons, what happens, guys?
Krish NAik: Can anybody tell me with respect to polygons?
Krish NAik: How polygons are being defined.
Krish NAik: How many of you know about segmentation?
Krish NAik: Just a quick idea, if you know, if you don't know, because there you have a lot of coordinates, X1, Y1, X2, Y2, X3, Y3, dot dot dot dot, till X and YN.
Krish NAik: Polygons are the best way, I can say, to get the exact piece of text, but again, in… whenever you are working with text, I can say BB boxes are much more better.
Krish NAik: With getting that, information. But polygons can also be used there.
Krish NAik: Polygons give you better and accurate results. That's why segmentation models, there you have lesser background noise, as compared to bounding boxes, where you always have some amount of background noise. There has to be there. With the object, always the noise remains, whereas segmentation models are better in that case.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: Building the legend, legend is, for all this, I can say, table, text, formula, algorithms, okay, for these type of things.
Krish NAik: each legend with respect to that, each color. Then comes, checking the PDF is available, so this is the Find PDF part. Then comes running the parcel. Now, this is the part where, actually, I'm, running the GLM OCR through Ulama.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like, both the options are there, whether you want to use the Z.EI, but here, in the ULAMA folder, it's very specific to ULAMA only and not z.ai API.
Krish NAik: And finally, saving the results into the output folder. So, JSON is the actual written type, but later on, I'm converting that JSON into a Markdown site.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now this format is directly not, thrown. You need to do the manual conversion of that JSON.
Krish NAik: And this, actually, this particular conversion, I have kept it in post-processing. If you really look into the doc parser, there is a script called as the post-processor.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can you see here? I'm just, showing you, like, this is the mapping that I have done.
Krish NAik: Based on that JSON.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, yes, document title, I'm converting it with a hash.
Krish NAik: Paragraph title, hashhash.
Krish NAik: Abstract, can you see?
Krish NAik: So, this is a simple mapping. The mapping can be much more, complicated, I can say, but this is a simple prompt map that I have kept it. That, okay, if from the JSON, if you're getting this information, this can be converted into a markdown. So, this is the markdown transformation map.
Krish NAik: It can be much more…
Krish NAik: I can say detailed one, but as we have worked majorly with archive-based papers, so this is the core structure.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, let's get back to our…
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, session state management. Now, this is, for the,
Krish NAik: Streamlit application, that I have kept it, and why I have kept it, I'm telling you the reason. Because, when you are actually browsing through a PDF, there are multiple pages. So what happens, okay, for one page, the model ran and gave you the answer, but once you…
Krish NAik: Scroll to the next page. If you are not using any type of, like, session state using Streamlit, then automatically that result will be moved. So, for that, the session state management that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, these are the sidebar settings where you upload the PDF, and then you click on run the parser, and finally you'll be getting the result.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, if you want to save the results, so that's why it's pre-saving the results into the output directory, so this is where that you have. From there, you will be loading the JSON file and rendering the results into the Streamlit application.
Krish NAik: So, this is not part of our app main application, but this was the main purpose of the Ollama folder, only for initial testing. So, what is… if I… simple terms, if I say, what is the use of this Olama folder?
Krish NAik: To test the performance of the layout model.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the main one.
Krish NAik: To test the performance of what? The layout detection. That is the main purpose, because here, getting the OCR, or getting the results of the OCR, that is the next thing. But just think about, if my layout detection is not correct, then for sure OCR, OCR will never be correct.
Krish NAik: Abhishek is asking, why we want to map the JSON into an empty? Just to do the rendering, no. See, in here I have that, output, I'm creating that markdown file, no.
Krish NAik: So, for that particular case, from JSON to that markdown manually, so for that particular transformation, I have done that mapping of Bishop.
Krish NAik: I hope… makes sense.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, let's start with, the scripts folder that I have now. This, particular scripts folder, is, like, every core functionality, I've kept it as an isolated script.
Krish NAik: Like, step-by-step, if you want to run it.
Krish NAik: So, as you can see here, the first phase is basically the parsing phase. If you look into parse. Okay, the CLI entry point for document parsing pipeline.
Krish NAik: If you want to start with the parsing part, so this is where, again, your GLM OCR. Now, initially, I started with separate scripts, and then I have started working on the SRC part.
Krish NAik: So, these scripts will directly come there.
Krish NAik: So, I'll be talking about this particular script directly inside the SRC.
Krish NAik: Then, after parsing, what is the next thing that happens, guys? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: After parsing.
Krish NAik: After passing, what is the next step?
Krish NAik: And just exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, now,
Krish NAik: After passing, so that's by ingestion CLI, first of all, parse the document, then comes your chunking, caption, embed, and upset to quadrant. Now, the same thing that I have added it with few CLI-based arguments.
Krish NAik: Okay, because initially I created the CLI application and then moved to a FastAPI-based application. So, I'll be talking about all these schema models are available inside your SRC, but just remember, first, parse, then ingest.
Krish NAik: After ingest, what is the next module that we'll be talking about?
Krish NAik: Which is the search module.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the main search module, because yes, here you'll be passing a query.
Krish NAik: To which Anirud is asking, I think this is run by, Flodu. Anir.
Krish NAik: Okay? GM40, GM4O, GPT4O, yes, this is the part where you actually make your query. Now, see, here I am not doing the generation, guys. Again, I'm repeating myself. Here, I was not worried about generation, because generation is simply one call that I attach it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, inside the script, there is no generation phase. So if you, really look into… here, simply, I was looking into the core retrieval part. With retrieval, I was testing my re-ranking. How many types of re-ranking backend that I have in this code?
Krish NAik: Guys, please let me know.
Krish NAik: How many types of re-ranking backend?
Krish NAik: Methach is telling 2.
Krish NAik: Others,
Krish NAik: Balaji is telling Jinnah 2, 2, 2. All right, so when I'll be getting into the get re-ranker, so in that module, we have total four
Krish NAik: Okay, one I have Jinna, one I have my Gwen, one I have my OpenAI through Prompt.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the other one is, BGM3, only for text redanke, that's why.
Krish NAik: All right, now, this is the core search part, so that's why here, no generation part.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes, finally, your SERP. What is the purpose of this SERP?
Krish NAik: This is the Fast API. If you want to run your Fast API application directly, you can use SERP.py also. Okay? Now, this file will simply start your application, the same one that you have inside SRC.
Krish NAik: Docparapiapp.vy, the same file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm telling. Now, these are some standalone scripts that I have kept just for initial testing, but later on, I'll be switching to the core SRC, where I'll be discussing function by function.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, coming to set GitHub secrets, now this is a simple script, like, if you want to set all of your secrets in one shot, in that case, you can use this bash script.
Krish NAik: So generally, you do, through your GitHub CLI, like, one secret, but if you don't want to copy-paste each of these things and to be picked up from your .env file, then you can use this script. So this is a simple automation that I have done, and you can see that, this is the simplest way. You can directly pass your ENV file, and from there.
Krish NAik: Those secrets will be automatically set for your GitHub repo.
Krish NAik: Then you have your warmup.py file. Now, what is the purpose of this warmup? I have kept the script in a separate way, so here, warmup means the models will be loaded once the container starts. It's very, very important. Otherwise.
Krish NAik: For your first request.
Krish NAik: The models will be downloaded. Okay, so the response time for your first request will be very, very high. So I was using this warmup.py script to load up the models. Okay, so you can see pre-warm both GPU models before the API server starts accepting traffic.
Krish NAik: So, simply, through the toxin, just try to understand. Otherwise, what will happen? When I run it, your first API call, then only the model will be loaded. So, in that case, what type of start we call it?
Krish NAik: Generally, for… What type of start we call it.
Krish NAik: Cold start, exactly correct. Okay, so in cold start, what happens? The first request, it will take a lot of time. But from the next request, at least, it will be faster. In our case, we know that these models really takes up a lot of time.
Krish NAik: So, for these things, I have kept this warmup.pa.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, and, and this is the core usage with respect to your, Docker infrastructure ecosystem only.
Krish NAik: So everything, by running this script, I was actually executing it through which I was making the model ready. So, it means that before the UVicon.
Krish NAik: Web server startup, the model should be…
Krish NAik: Alright, this was the main purpose of warmup.py, and this infrastructure, actually, I was only using
Krish NAik: With respect to Docker Compose, not for our local.
Krish NAik: local, it is a cold start, but for our deployment, I was using this warmup.py start.
Krish NAik: Fine. Now, these are the core scripts that I have.
Krish NAik: Now, let's start with our…
Krish NAik: core application part. Now, in this application, few things are normals. It means you guys already know what are the things that you don't know, and which is completely new, which is the chunker.val.
Krish NAik: Now, out of this entire application, if I say that, what is the new thing? That is chunker.pway, okay? Because really, here,
Krish NAik: Inside a single chunking, I have two types of strategies, I will let you know. It means that a single-based strategy that I have, and an entire document-based strategy. While becoming that. So, Mitas, you're still in confused one more broad?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, warm-up is for, your warm start, not for your cold. Cold is by default, Methish.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why I'm telling I'm actually using that warmup.py, where in your Docker Compose set.
Krish NAik: Because during our deployment, it's not necessary. For our local testing, it's pretty much full start on LinkedIn.
Krish NAik: So, warmup.py is for your warm start.
Krish NAik: Okay? By default, the application is, cold, start, locally, if you are doing it.
Krish NAik: So, the most important file is the config.py, and I think this is the file everybody has already gone through. Yes, on?
Krish NAik: So, Paul, in organization, with this, it doesn't this, like, king, there are a lot of other things that can be added, but, it's just a stacking benchmark, Rajit. Always take it, because…
Krish NAik: Complexities can be much more in real time.
Krish NAik: And have you developed this one. Yes, Pratamesh. Majorly, like, ported some cloth hood and GLM 5.1, these two that I majorly… these three that I majorly…
Krish NAik: And I will say all three experiences good. Even Kimi 2.5. I forgot, this week, Kimi 2.6 also came. 2.6 is also really, really good.
Krish NAik: I've tested Kimi 2.6, and I think in OpenCode you can get it, I think they have 3X access, that is also good.
Krish NAik: SPU have shown most of the steps components, but in this project, that covers all the 12
Krish NAik: Semantic hybrid, background… Oh, bullets.
Krish NAik: Okay, escape. Now, that is a, different one, that, but, you are talking about, specific extraction, structure preservation, chunking, metadata enrichment to ensure, and we are self-saving for everything downstream.
Krish NAik: In a single project, I don't keep all the steps, because I really, like,
Krish NAik: In every project, I keep certain components that can be later on accumulated and brought.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I think, this one, that you have kept it, but I will say majorly, all of the things, more things that you can keep it from security perspective, few things still that are missing.
Krish NAik: Kimi, what is Kimi? Kimi is also a good model. Thanks for your suggestion, needed for production. All right. For production, you can add more and more things.
Krish NAik: Just be sure everything that does needs to be added, it totally depends upon your latency. I feel that in… till now, in this course, I've told you.
Krish NAik: The main problem with a rack-based system is you can add more and more components, everything is plug-and-play. But whenever you are adding a component, the latency matters. I don't feel like everything that needs to be attached.
Krish NAik: If you don't have any, constraint on your latency part, it means that, okay, fine, you might get a response after 3 minutes, 4 minutes, really, it doesn't matter. In that case, you can add each and every component.
Krish NAik: But I feel that, majorly, everybody has a requirement that it should be under 500 millisecond or 600 milliseconds.
Krish NAik: That's why, in that case, a lot of companies, that needs to be removed, at least. The document ingestion pipeline can take inning, because that is the most high-quality thing
Krish NAik: As compared to retrieval and the generation fields. I feel that the document ingestion should be of your highest worth.
Krish NAik: If it is bad, nothing the retrieval can do, neither your re-ranking can do, neither your generation can do.
Krish NAik: All right. Pratham is, really, like, that is not really required, like, how I use Cloud.
Krish NAik: Needed for… okay. Now, I think, this is the core settings, the config… how many of you have gone through config.tv? Because really, this script, I think everybody has gone through whenever you have been executing so many branches. Because in multiple classes, we have worked with the main branch, deployment branch, quand branch, three major branches that I have worked with.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few things that I have changed. Right now, this is the deployment branch. So, the major changes are…
Krish NAik: So, if you look into the parser backend, I have kept the cloud version as well as the OLAMA. So, in our .env file, it is… the backend is OLAMA, the default version is the z.api one.
Krish NAik: If I am using z.api, in that case, only the API key is required. Log level info, output directory, now this is the main output directory, okay, that I have kept it. Then, config.yml. Now, this config.yml is for your ULAMA.
Krish NAik: Then come here,
Krish NAik: OpenAI, secret key, what is the model that I am using, the GP24 rule?
Krish NAik: embedding provider. So, three embedding providers are there in the codebase. So, I think, we have… I think two embedding providers are the OpenAI, Gemini, and, here, text embedding 3 Large and 3072, but it can be overridden with
Krish NAik: Text embedding 3 small with 1536 dimension. That is also fine, you can override it through your .env file.
Krish NAik: Now, Gemini API key, if you are really working with Gemini, new embedding model that got launched last month, that is also fine. That is pure multimodal embedding.
Krish NAik: Then comes your quadrant, so locally, we are running it, so that's why the local host information, if you want a cloud
Krish NAik: infra, in that case, just be sure you are updating the host URL and the API key. These things are pretty much
Krish NAik: I think you guys have done it multiple times, you should be comfortable with. Then comes the re-ranker backend. Initially, so STR, so here I've kept it, the default one as OpenAI. Later on, you can switch to Jenna. In Jenna, you have, I think, 10 million token limit. That is quite enough to do the initial testing.
Krish NAik: OpenAI is there, then comes your VGM3, re-ranker backend, that is also there. Then you have the VL re-ranker backend, which I've used in the Quinn branch.
Krish NAik: So there, I have actually switched it. The re-ranker top end, again, now these are the default values. Again, it can be changed during your inference phase.
Krish NAik: Then here, the JINA API key.
Krish NAik: I think… we have used it, somewhere around, I think, in the main branches.
Krish NAik: Then, now here, a few things with respect to, captioning, with respect to tables and images, that information. So here, max tokens that I have kept it as 2,000. Now, table max tokens, it means that for tables also, I was generating few captions.
Krish NAik: Now, I felt that, initially I started with 512, but, if you're getting bigger tables, then that 512 is not
Krish NAik: Generating the max output tokens.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the max output token that I have kept it as 2000.
Krish NAik: Now, initially, I've kept it table max input characters, the max that I am sending for table caption. That is, like, 12 underscore 1000. Later on, I can actually increase it more, because I really don't know what is the size of the tables that we'll be working with.
Krish NAik: It can be one entire page is complete table. In that case, just be sure you play out with these values. I've kept it a rough around, but if you feel that your entire page is fully your table and there is nothing, in that case, please increase the max number of tokens also at least to 4096 or something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay. Rasana is asking, okay, now this is one question. Hi, Paul, can you please tell me where we can fit Gleaner 2 in this like before?
Krish NAik: We will be fitting it where? A simple question, Prasanna is asking, really, this is a great one, I have already taught you about Gliner 2 and Lang extract. Guys, tell me, where should I include Gliner 2 if I'm working with this codebase?
Krish NAik: It will be here.
Krish NAik: this is the main part, okay, and the chunker.py, the chunker.py, I will come to that, but, with respect to your chunk information, because, see, Rasana, what will happen?
Krish NAik: And now here, once you have done the chunking.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you have the chunk information with you. Now, the portion comes, if you have text, it's fine, it works.
Krish NAik: Okay, because Gleaner V2 doesn't support, like, multimodal, you cannot pass images there.
Krish NAik: But if you are working with immediate chunks, or table chunks, or algorithm chunks, or formula chunks, in that case.
Krish NAik: After the captioning part, you have to use Gleaner 2.
Krish NAik: For text chunks, directly you can pass it.
Krish NAik: But for your multimodal chunks, in simple terms, multimodal, I'm treating as the table one algorithm. In that case, once you have done the captioning, then you can use Gleaner retool there.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Anilut is telling Quit. Quit is, regarding what?
Krish NAik: ingestion, okay. Because once you have the… some type of checked, at least captioning-based information, then on top of the caption data, you can actually pass.
Krish NAik: Because if you have just a simple image on top of that multimodal image, your Gleaner V2 cannot work. I hope everybody understands that.
Krish NAik: Later on, they might come up with multimodal support, but right now, there is no support for that metadata extraction. Joe is telling metadata, yes, that's the purpose of Glenar V2.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: No, Here, initially, the table use vision, like, for tables, if you want to.
Krish NAik: use, like, on top of tables directly, you can apply OCR, because, the model will throw you an output, in the form of a markdown. Otherwise, if you want to use the base64 in that case, so by default, I have kept it full, but you can keep it as true as well
Krish NAik: Now, a few simple fast API settings, initially. The API workers, host and port, logging, JForms, initially, I've kept it as false. Now, this is a model validator backend. Now, this I am always checking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is pretty much a singleton call, I can say. So, with respect to your every call, this will be checked. Now, what is the core thing? So, the one is a parser backend with respect to your data ingestion phase, that will be checked.
Krish NAik: Now comes your config.yml, your ulamaconfig.yml. Okay, so I have kept the, core ULAMA model loading part here.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the config.yml that I have for ULA, and you can see what type of, attributes as per PPDocLayout attributes, which has been mentioned in the official technical report of, PPDocLayout, based on that I have kept.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this particular format, from where I have taken, I have taken it from the official GLM OCR docs.
Krish NAik: which is available in the official GitHub repo of JLMOCR.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's get back to our config.py. Anything else? Now, this is the get settings, and finally, configure the login part. Login part, even I have added it, in our middleware, also, of ASCIQ.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, I think everybody is pretty much comfortable with this file, because this is pretty much self-explanatory.
Krish NAik: Any other things are there, you can let me know in the chat, okay? Now, comes here, login config. Now, here I have used LogGuru.
Krish NAik: You can use any other libraries that you have used for logging purely with Python. You guys can let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, please let me know. StructLog, you know, struct log is also good,
Krish NAik: I will say, for beginners, it's better, but if you are actually… you have used log guru, then try to make a switch. It's…
Krish NAik: Little bit harder.
Krish NAik: As compared to local. But yes, that is much better, getting structured logging.
Krish NAik: Now, here, set up a, login. So, initially.
Krish NAik: I have kept everything to info level, but later on, you can change it to debug level also. For a few of the things that I have actually added to debug level info, in some cases, with respect to JLM, the passing part, very specifically, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, core things, everything will be rendered in your terminal, that's why it says.standardout. The level, which is the info level by default that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, initially, I've kept it false, but you can change the value in the config file, config.py, and you can update what type of, if you want to save everything in one shot.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the format, the green and sign colors, two colors that I am maintaining. Okay, and with respect to our middleware also, where, very specifically, I'm passing it to the UVicon, so if you check my API, and if you check the middleware.py, so here also the logging middleware that I have added.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, a very similar implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the core logging module that I have in this application.
Krish NAik: Now, I will come to…
Krish NAik: The first part, which is your,
Krish NAik: Let's start with chunker.pa, because I feel that other rest of the code is pretty much self-explanatory, only the image captioning file has been changed in the when branch.
Krish NAik: Okay, two files are very, very important to discuss. So, let's start with our chunker.py and why this file is a little bit unique. Let's talk about that.
Krish NAik: So, in this particular file, there are two types of chunker that I have used, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, when I say two types of chunking, so one is the document-aware chunking, okay, and it's the structure-aware chunking. Now, similarly, you will see that the terms are being used. The other, what is the term?
Krish NAik: Any other term that you might have used, another term which is called layout-aware chunking.
Krish NAik: Another is asking which is better, strut locked is better.
Krish NAik: As compared to LogGuru. It has a more added functionality out there.
Krish NAik: From production point of view. But for your initial development, always start with logarithms, switch to structuring.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, let's talk about our chunking, guys. Everybody, please focus on this part, because this is where things are a little bit interesting, that I feel. A lot of, things, with respect to, the core part, that I have changed. So, two core implementations that I have kept.
Krish NAik: The first part is that there are two fallback conditions. One is that how you want to do the chunking? Do you want to do it page by page, or do you want to do the chunking for an entire document in one shot? Which is a better approach, please tell me that.
Krish NAik: I want to really understand from your perspectives.
Krish NAik: Which is better, page by page?
Krish NAik: Or the entire document in one shot.
Krish NAik: wrote it.
Krish NAik: Yeah, alright. Now, see, when I told both the things, we have to analyze the documents.
Krish NAik: Page-by-page approach is good, I will say, when you are working much more with technical documents, research papers in those cases.
Krish NAik: Because in page-by-page approach, what happens, you have to, first of all, understand that, okay, if you feel that, okay, let's take one page. Just think about, there is a certain attribute, let's take a simple paragraph.
Krish NAik: Now, that paragraph, only one part is there in one page. In the other, page, there is the next part. Then what will happen in that case?
Krish NAik: think, because your OCR model that you have used, that also cannot do, because every OCR model will be working on page by page only.
Krish NAik: So there will be… that needs to be overlap.
Krish NAik: Yes or no. So, you have to think about that which approach that you want to do it, page by page, or a complete document in one shot. It means that, just think about a bucket. In that bucket, first, you'll be looking into page
Krish NAik: 1. In that page, we have gone through, now in the last part, when you look into, okay, now let's look for any, attribute which is incomplete. It means that the starting point and the ending point, you can always analyze it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now you can keep adding those information step by step into your main bucket. So that is a very similar approach that we have done it. So, here, with respect to your chunking.
Krish NAik: What is the first phase?
Krish NAik: Excuse me, guys, let me just drink some water.
Krish NAik: So, what is the first phase? The GLM OCR, it will go. So, it means that your parsing will be initialized. After the parsing, what are the things that will be returned? It's basically your paragraph, titles, tables, algorithms, and these things.
Krish NAik: The first phase is parsing. Then comes your next phase, which is this… your chunker.py phase, where your chunking will start. So, elements will be grouped into chunks.
Krish NAik: Now, this is very, very important, because I want the elements to be grouped into chunks. And what are those mean categories?
Krish NAik: That I have defined, so let's start with the first one.
Krish NAik: So, right now, for every chunk that I'll be maintaining a proper data class, okay, now, I have kept my schemas here, schemas.py. So, here, if you really look into chunk result now, see, this is the core chunk result.
Krish NAik: Now, here, what are the core things? One is the chunk ID. This is unique. Now, text.
Krish NAik: inside that chunk, whatever the text is available. Then comes your source file, page number, modality. If you look into this modality, I told you modality is the core. How many modalities that we have in our application?
Krish NAik: How many modalities that I have?
Krish NAik: Three modalities?
Krish NAik: No. The total number of modalities that we have in our code is… one is text, one is image, one is table, one is algorithm, one is formula. So, 5.
Krish NAik: Five, core modalities that we are working with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a chunk result that I have, guys. Okay, now, let's get back to our chunker.py. Now, let's start, first of all, with the atomic labels. Why atomic? I want to say that, okay, if this is a chunk.
Krish NAik: I want that chunk to be complete. It means that… can I say that for a single table, it's a good practice to keep two different chunks?
Krish NAik: Do you think that it's a good practice?
Krish NAik: I should keep it in a single unified chunk yes or no.
Krish NAik: So, always remember that. Now the, question comes… it's a very rare scenario where your table might be a…
Krish NAik: more than one page. Majorly, I'm taking the assumption that in a single page, your entire table will be there. But even if your table is two pages, then also you have to take both that information and keep it as an atomic unit.
Krish NAik: Rather than breaking stuff in between. That's a very bad practice. So.
Krish NAik: Here, I have taken this one. So, one is the token what ratio. Now, by default, every type of GPT models are taking this particular factor of 1.38, because I'm not counting each and each token.
Krish NAik: Computationally, it is a much more expensive task, that's why I've taken a token word ratio. And 1.3, 1.4, these are the default multiplexer values that we do take it.
Krish NAik: So, whatever the word count, just multiply by that.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can take tick token, and you can count every point of time.
Krish NAik: Now, the atomic labels set that I have defined, one is for table, one is for formula, inline formula, algorithm, image, and figure. Now, can I say that these are all multimodal things? I have not kept text here, because text is fine. I can keep text
Krish NAik: broken into, like, 2 chunks, 3 chunks, or 4 chunks. Because there I have a certain condition also. What is the minimum chunk size?
Krish NAik: If you look into, so I think it was around 512 data we have taken.
Krish NAik: Now, for text, I'm maintaining that, but for table and formula, I'm telling that you can overwrite that.
Krish NAik: Because if I'm not overriding it, creating an atomic unit is not possible.
Krish NAik: So, for atomic levels that I have, I'm simply telling that, yes, for table, for formula, for inline formula, for algorithm, for image, or for figures, always maintain atomic chunks. It means that in a single chunk, you should have the entire information.
Krish NAik: Okay, whereas for text mortality, I am not maintaining that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, title labels according to the, output of the parser, where I have, like, paragraph titles, document titles, figure titles, okay? Now, that's why I'm creating two frozen set forms.
Krish NAik: Now, modality classification sets. So, right here, if you look into the modality classification set, so these are what? Can I say that these are pretty much all multimodal set? Yes or no?
Krish NAik: The image type, the table type, the formula type, and the algorithm type.
Krish NAik: Because when you look into the frozen set, now, these are the attribute values which are being returned by WOOM.
Krish NAik: These values, like image, table, inline formula, algorithm, image, and figure, this is written by whom?
Krish NAik: Which phase guy?
Krish NAik: By which model?
Krish NAik: By your parser, yes, by your…
Krish NAik: Rather than using the term parser, use the term your actual layout detection model.
Krish NAik: Okay, because that is the return type. Your document parser throws the OCR also.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, so, that's why, initially, I've done the frozen set, this part.
Krish NAik: Now, right now, if you, simply look into label, text, bounding box, core, more attributes are there, but initially, for the core, I can say classification, I have taken only this one. I feel that image types can be kept under this. If you have more attributes related to images, you can add it here.
Krish NAik: For example, one simplest example, if I say you, If they have charts.
Krish NAik: So, where you will add charts? In the modality classification set. Quickly tell.
Krish NAik: If you have charts, a simple written type, where you will add it. In the image types, Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, comes, the infirm modality. Okay, so here, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: So, derive the chunk modality from the element levels. Now, from where I'll be getting the element levels from the output of the layout detection model.
Krish NAik: So, return type, image table formula. So, in that way, simply, I can say that, okay, this is my core infirm modality. So, the total types of modality from here, it will become clear to you.
Krish NAik: So, my output type, 1, 2, 3, 4. Okay, so majorly, like, return type image, return type table, return type formula, return type algorithm, or the default category of unimodal, which is the text part.
Krish NAik: So, right now, even I have not started chunking. What I'm working on?
Krish NAik: modality classification. It means that the result that I'll be getting from the parsing, I need to do the classification, the information that I'm getting.
Krish NAik: Because… Once I have that information, then only the text can cite that matters. Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Directly looking into the text is not worth it. Why?
Krish NAik: If I don't have the attributes with me.
Krish NAik: Then, what is the added benefit?
Krish NAik: That's why you always first work on the attributes part.
Krish NAik: Okay, and always remember, These attributes will change according to your layout model… layout detection model.
Krish NAik: It means that already, in class, I have shown you for dockling.
Krish NAik: Okay, Docling uses the Heron models. There, this output will be different. Minor you. It uses a, Doc YOLO variant, YOLOX variant. There, the output of the attribute type is different. So, guys, always remember this set of attributes, I cannot fix it.
Krish NAik: It totally depends upon the output of your layout detection mode.
Krish NAik: Alright, so right now, the core part with respect to your classification is done, and here, simply I'm telling that, okay, now these are the atomic labels, these are the title labels, okay, so that's for multiple buckets, that I have. So one bucket that I have kept it is for our atomic labels.
Krish NAik: And the other bucket that I have is for our title levels, because under this.
Krish NAik: So, under this, I can keep my, like, image, figure, and under, that, I can say modality, and this is my text modality handling that I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so document title, paragraph title, and figure title.
Krish NAik: So, two buckets for now. Later on, I'll be working on this particular bucket, and I'll be adding the information step by step.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, coming to…
Krish NAik: a generic class that I have created, a class chunk, a rag-ready document chunk, and this is the schema model that I have kept it. Already, I've shown you, inside your schemas.py, inside the API folder, you have this tool.
Krish NAik: So here, first of all, text. So, by default, in a chunk, we will be looking for text that chunk text content or AI caption for the image chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally for image chunks, so don't think only for image chunks, it can be for table chunks also. If you are doing the captioning for images, tables in that way, that information will be added here.
Krish NAik: Now, a separate, field that I have, even for AI-generated caption text.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is the same output, so you can think about this output and this output, and why I have kept it, this output, you can think about… in the text, there are two conditions. One is the original text in your document and paragraph that you will be getting, but only
Krish NAik: The differentiator is that, if you have your normal text version, then that will be the normal text, the original text that you have inside your document title, paragraph title, or your figure title.
Krish NAik: Then comes your unique identifier, alright. Then comes your page number.
Krish NAik: Okay, so page number and the, chunk name. So, we'll be maintaining page across, like, we'll be maintaining the page number with your chunk ID. It means that a continuous list of chunks that I'll be maintaining. In that way, I know the structure.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it means that if… how many of you remember the output?
Krish NAik: there used to have your page number with your chunk ID. So, initially, in your page 1, there would be chunk 1, chunk 2, chunk 3, let's take. In page 2, what you will have.
Krish NAik: Chunk 4, 5, 6, page 3, what you will have?
Krish NAik: Similarly, 789, if I'm assuming that every page has 3 chunks in that way I'm doing a simple assumption. Then, you will be always maintaining that each number with respect to chunk that will become.
Krish NAik: Now, the element types, so list of element labels included in this chunk, very, very important. So, from here, you understand that, okay, so this is the type of attribute that I'm getting from the parser. Then comes your bounding box coordinates for that particular chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally for text chunks, it will be none. If you are working with images, tables, in that case, this bounding box value is important.
Krish NAik: What if a chunk crosses a page? We will come to that. Right now, I'm not started about the chunking mechanism biology. In that case, we have to add that information into your older chunk.
Krish NAik: Then comes the original file, isAtomic. Now, this isAtomic is the condition where you'll be having your multimodality. So, like, tables, formulas, only in that case, it will be true. For text, it will be false.
Krish NAik: If you feel that, in a single chunk, the entire information is there, only in that case it will be true. So measly, I will say that for your multimodalities, only it will be true, but in text cases.
Krish NAik: If the text chunk is very, very small, in that case, only its atomic true condition will come for your text.
Krish NAik: Now comes your, modality, so text, image, table. Now, what is the purpose of this modality?
Krish NAik: Now, this is where you can actually use it through your metadata also.
Krish NAik: in your vector store, if you save this information later on, if you, if you remember, I think during our inference phase, we were using that modality, part.
Krish NAik: Whenever I was doing the searching. So, in that case, very specifically, text, image, table, formula, and algorithm, I can directly. So, pretty much optimize search directly. You can think about a metadata filtering operation.
Krish NAik: Then comes base 64 encoded PNG of the cropped region, stated by the image captioner. Okay, now this is your original base64 value.
Krish NAik: And these values, I'm maintaining for image only. Images and tables, I'm not maintaining it for your other attributes, like
Krish NAik: formula.
Krish NAik: algorithms for those things, I am not maintaining, guys. Okay, later on, you can maintain those things also in your vector tool.
Krish NAik: Now, caption part. Now, this is the original captioning. So, generally, for image modalities, these two things will be pretty much same, because I thought about just to create a separate field just for pure caption.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if it's a multimodal chunk, like text table, then both the cases, the value will be the same. If it is only text, in that case, there will be no captioning. So captioning is only enabled for how many things? Your four attributes, table, formulas, images, and algorithms. Not for your text.
Krish NAik: I'm doing image caption.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: So majorly, these are the main schemas that I have kept it. Okay, now this is the identity code definition.
Krish NAik: Okay, so one is the estimated tokens that I have kept it. So, right now, I am taking it as 1.3, you can take it as 1.4 or 1.5 also, these are the default values. If you want to do an estimated token count, I'm not doing an exact, accurate token count.
Krish NAik: That is much more costlier operation, so I've taken an approximate operation.
Krish NAik: now comes, split text, into sub-charms. Now.
Krish NAik: This is the part where your atomic unit condition, like, a single unit, can be broken into multiple subchards.
Krish NAik: So, here takes the maximum number of tokens, so in our case, I think we are meeting the 512.
Krish NAik: So, split a single large tech stock look into chunks that fit with the max token. So, here, based on that, particular conditions, I have kept it. And I think you can look into, I think, somewhere, based on the max chunks value that I have taken it, it's around 512. You can increase it much more.
Krish NAik: So, splitting on white spaces boundaries to avoid cutting off mid-wood, so…
Krish NAik: Now, this is a simple Python-based operation on top of that, and here, the max in token divided by the word ratio that I have taken. So, from there, roughly, always the value will be around
Krish NAik: less than your highest number. So, always, like, 10%, it will be toward the lower side.
Krish NAik: Now, this function is the most important function in our implementation, which is the document aware chunking, because till now, this is the split text data that I'll be using it in the next function, and this is the estimated tokens.
Krish NAik: Now, those two are pretty much like helper functions in our chunky. Now, here, what I have done it, I will be chunking the whole document. It means that across all paths.
Krish NAik: Across all pages, in a single pass.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, why I've taken this approach?
Krish NAik: First of all, I can maintain my overlap of any chunk that comes into the picture, so in a single pass, the entire chunking that I'll be doing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is added benefit. There won't be any type of problems with respect to any overlapping, but if you feel that, you need page-by-page, a single-page-page approach, there is a fallback condition also that I have kept it. I think, where is that condition?
Krish NAik: This is a structure of action. Okay, so two different pages here. Now, this is a single page element.
Krish NAik: operation. And this is the entire document of our chunk tool.
Krish NAik: So always remember that, when you are defining, so, how
Krish NAik: document our chunking is different from structure of our chunking. Generally, most of the structure of our chunking
Krish NAik: you do it page by page. So, one page, chunking, next page, chunking, three page. But, you don't do chunk of the entire document in one shot. So, here, a little bit different with respect to the document. So, here, I will be doing the entire chunking in one shot.
Krish NAik: Have you been, how are you building the metadata? Metadata part,
Krish NAik: I think only I have kept one metadata field, that is the poor, mortality part.
Krish NAik: Okay, which I have taken through with the frozen set classification. So this is the core input.
Krish NAik: not done here, metadata. I don't know whether you have executed the project or not. In that project, any specific metadata filtering that I have not added, only based on those tags, I have added it manually during your inferencing part.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so first of all, let's start with our documentation. So.
Krish NAik: the list of pages, the total 9 pages or 10 pages, whatever, everything will be coming in one shop. And all the elements. Okay, now you have to think about the output of document that we are changing page by page.
Krish NAik: So, don't think about, like, initially we will start with one page, then two page, so that call will be a single call, not multi-call, like, per page call won't happen.
Krish NAik: On top of the entire document. And what is the added benefit? Because already the written type of the JSON that I have. So, if I show you the output of the parser.
Krish NAik: Where is the output of the password? So, let's take something like an LM. So, can I say that in this particular file, I have the information about my all pages, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, guys, please tell me.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because how you can do document-aware chunking, that is the first, because I'm not looking into PDF pages. I'm looking into the output of
Krish NAik: Layout detection plus OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I try to always understand, on top of what I'm applying the chunking mechanism.
Krish NAik: The core chunking is applied on top of the output of the parsing. It means that I'm not looking into the PDF anymore. Whatever the structure that has been thrown as an output, only on top of that I'm looking in.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, let's get back to our core file.
Krish NAik: what is the best file to go? Go with JSON.
Krish NAik: File, because that .md file, I am actually creating that from the JSON protocol. So, the JSON is the main out…
Krish NAik: Poor person.
Krish NAik: Hold on.
Krish NAik: head back to our, chunking. Okay, so here, across all pages into a single pass. Unlike structure of our chunking, single page, this process, every page as continuous element stream, so that… Okay, now, that is the second function which I'm really not using it.
Krish NAik: Now, rules, pretty much similar as structure of chunking. Now, the only thing is extended for cross-page. Now, if I do a cross-page operation, then actually I can relate it. Then only I can maintain the atomic element also.
Krish NAik: Because if you really look, yes, majorly the figure, the figure title, in that case, it can mean different, or probably, if such cases comes. Because I feel that, figure and figure title should be kept as a single atomic unit, yes or no.
Krish NAik: How many of you think that it should be yes or no?
Krish NAik: Figure is a different output of your OCR.
Krish NAik: Or your layout detection. Similarly, the figure type. The idea is that
Krish NAik: If I can keep it as an atomic unit, it makes much more sense.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why whenever there is a figure followed by a figure title, I will always keep it as a single atomic movement.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, see, you have to think about, this is pretty much generic, everybody should have, but again, like, if you don't have all the information just, because there are certain conditions, if you don't have an image title or a figure title, in that case, really, this concept doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Because in every research paper it handles, but every document in the world doesn't follow that same structure.
Krish NAik: Can you also add the title as a metadata? Yes, that document title or the figure title, that value will be their addition. You can handle that.
Krish NAik: Figure type.
Krish NAik: But that title will be Type Text, so you have to look for that sequence.
Krish NAik: If you have that particular sequence with you from the JSON, if you have that, you can use it.
Krish NAik: Correct. Now, so this is the atomic element rule that I have been using it. Figure title is intercepted before the atomic flush and pretended to be.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I'm using a flusher function, I'll be coming to the flusher function and what is the main purpose of this, and prepend it, to the figures as the image trunk text, so the caption and the visuals are co-located. Now, this is the main part which, I have added it, figure with respect to figure title.
Krish NAik: So, it means… and figure underscore title is what type of modality?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me, Figure underscore title is what type of modality, guys?
Krish NAik: It is text, okay. So it means that I am doing a fusion between text modality and the image modality.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, it becomes easier to send me that information as an atomic unit to the LLM for our generation phase, or even to our re-rankers. The quality of the output becomes better.
Krish NAik: Then comes section slash document slash paragraph titles, each forward to the next content element, even across a page boundary. Now, through the flusher, I am actually handling it. Okay, I'm using the term atomic flush. I'll be coming to that flush, exactly what is a flush.
Krish NAik: Flush means, like, removing all the elements and start, fresh, but within that single pass. Okay, so I've dedicated function as there for the flush operation to be taken, please.
Krish NAik: Now, yes, we need to maintain the overlap. Now, that's why section, paragraph titles, everything will be. If any overlap comes across two different pages, it will be handled.
Krish NAik: Text elements accumulate up to max chunk tokens. So, max, like, let's take the example of 512.
Krish NAik: After that, what will overflow starts a new chunk. It means that if it crosses that particular condition, automatically new chunk, but for which modality? Only for text elements that I am telling. For others, not.
Krish NAik: Then, jump page is set to page of the first element that entered the chunk. So, we'll be always looking into what is the first element.
Krish NAik: Of every page. Then, in that way, it becomes easier for me to track also, okay? So, generally, like, if it is a paragraph, then we can actually have a check with your last chunk of the last page, with the first chunk of the second page. Then, also, we can…
Krish NAik: apply a flush operation. What is that? Flush, in simple terms, means that your existing chunk, from the second chunk, you can… will be picking up that value and inserting it in your old chunk. In that way, you create
Krish NAik: That, complete atomic unit with respect to your multimodalities, or a new chunk unit based on the condition of 512,
Krish NAik: in the same unit, or make a new chunk. So, that flush operation will come.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, so let's start. Now, this is the docsing, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, let's start with the first one.
Krish NAik: Now, all pairs, so here are a few things. Page number with element. Now, why this pair that I am maintaining, guys? If you look into the output, I was maintaining two things. Now, this is maintained in my schema part. Page number and the chunk came from.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if I am actually creating a pair, it means page number with a chunk, that's why that particular information, I am maintaining it.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: Now, if not all pairs, then return is equal to blank, but if most of the time this condition will be satisfied.
Krish NAik: all key pairs with respect to the reading orders that I have.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, let's start with the blank. Now, this is your bucket. You can think about this bucket. I'll be filling it up step by step.
Krish NAik: Now, the flush operation will be, adding each of the flush in one step.
Krish NAik: Now, let's start,
Krish NAik: How many of you understand the operation of a flat-end? Generally, the flat-end operation, I think everybody understands flat-end in deep learning.
Krish NAik: Please let me know flatten operation.
Krish NAik: when you convert a, high-dimension data into a one-dimensional data. Okay, so similarly, you have to think about here what we are doing. We are converting, that all number of pages, okay, into a single, a flattened information.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, because you have 10 pages, all that 10 pages information, I'll be keeping it in a single list, or just like a single bucket. So that's why I'm telling you this is a chunk flattening operation that we are doing. Initially, the chunk index will start with 0,
Krish NAik: Now, this is the accumulator stage. So, flushing and the accumulation. Two stage happen. Flush means
Krish NAik: remove everything, proceed with the next step of accumulation. Accumulation, where it is required, Guys, accumulation means
Krish NAik: whenever you have, one chunk, in the next space, another chunk, when you feel that there is an overlap. In that case, accumulation is required, yes or no.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys.
Krish NAik: What is the concept of accumulator here? That is the state of the accumulator.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that whenever you might have an overlap between the pages, to handle that overlap, you will be doing the accumulation of the new text
Krish NAik: into your older chunk from the previous page, if the continuation of the chunk happened. So, in that case, I'm maintaining a current text, current labels, current tokens, and current. So, this is a simple state.
Krish NAik: And this state is for your older chunk, because later on, after the accumulation, this state will be updated.
Krish NAik: Then comes your, pending title, pending, label page. Okay, now, this I'm maintaining as a section title, because
Krish NAik: Whenever there is a chunk, for that chunk, if there is a very specific section, or any type of caption that comes, okay, it always needs to be handed. So that's why that particular state will always remain the same.
Krish NAik: Even if the chunk, just think about part of the chunk is in page 2, but the, title…
Krish NAik: page or that particular heading was in your, before page, like in page 1. So, we know that we have to maintain the title similar, because the title won't change as per your page 2. That's why I'm maintaining a similar state.
Krish NAik: Now comes your, accumulator, then comes flush. What is the meaning of flush?
Krish NAik: Simply remove everything. Okay, so flush current state.
Krish NAik: It means that once your accumulator state is completed, then the flushing operation will take place. So here, def, flush, current, non-local values, the current text, current labels, current tokens, chunk IDs. Now, these are all the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, similarly, non-local, pending type… Since now, I have passed pending title label, pending title page, and everything.
Krish NAik: So, I am handling this value. So, you can think about these are pretty much about, symbols…
Krish NAik: state management in a flattening state of entire, I can say, document features that is being handed.
Krish NAik: How many of you can understand? This is pure state management of the chunks that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: In a single pass.
Krish NAik: Sometimes I need to empty, because if one chunk is completed, can I say that you need to empty the bucket, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because you have one bucket. For one chunk, you are getting the information.
Krish NAik: If there is some type of overlap, you are using the accumulator state, and you are completing that chunk. But after the chunk is completed, I have to say that, yes, I need to empty the bucket.
Krish NAik: Then, again, for the next chunk, again, I will start filling up the value. If, again, anything overlap comes, again, I'll be initializing the accumulator. It will fill up the chunk. Then, again, I need to flush it. Then, again, I will make the bucket empty.
Krish NAik: Then again, I have to add to the bucket, if I get an overlap condition, then again, the accumulator state.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands the flow.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you it's a simple state management.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that, first of all, take the information. If any overlap is there, accumulator will be, activated. Accumulator task is done, it means that you need to empty the bucket. Let's start with our next job. This is the core object of your flush.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you look into if not, current text and current text is none, then return. Then by default.
Krish NAik: the return will be activated, okay? And, most of the cases, only a chance will be completed, so these states will have some values.
Krish NAik: And can you see the return type of this function? What is the return type? None. None means what?
Krish NAik: Guys, none means what?
Krish NAik: remove everything from the bucket, can I say? That's why I've kept it as none.
Krish NAik: Please try to always look into the type hinting of the function, from there you will get an idea. So, two, pure states, one is the accumulative state that I have added, one is the flushing state that I have added.
Krish NAik: But, like, now,
Krish NAik: Once the flush is done, your final chunk will be ready, so that's why the core part information of the chunk
Krish NAik: I know that the final chunk is ready. After that, your flush will be initialized. It means that the bucket has been cleared for your next chunk to be made.
Krish NAik: And finally, everything, I am appending it to chunks.append. So, in your core chunk, bucket, the final things, I think, which is a blank one, somewhere that I… I have created a blank chunk, I think. I forgot. So… somewhere here. You can see list of chunks. So, this is where your new chunk will be gathered.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, core flush part is done. Now, this is the structure of our chunking, though I'm not using it, guys, in the actual codebase, but I have kept it. Like, if you really want to use the structure of our chunking, where you won't be treating entirely the overlapping conditions, in that case, you can use it.
Krish NAik: Okay, in this case, what happens for multi-page document preference?
Krish NAik: I will say that document-aware chunking is much better, but if you feel that only you need to focus on one page.
Krish NAik: whether the chunk is incomplete or not, you are not really worried about that, then you can go ahead with structure of action. A very similar approach that I have done it here.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, here, page by page, it will be, so…
Krish NAik: I feel that this is of lesser use, because our core information is this accumulator and the flusher state, and I will say that always in… because this implementation is inspired by one of the implementations of layout… layout documentware chunking from AWS that I have taken.
Krish NAik: So, in chunking, now this… I don't think any direct chunking is there anywhere, whether it's in Langchen, or in Llama Index, or in Chongqi.
Krish NAik: these type of chunkers directly not there, but you will be having your structure layout changes. So, page by page, you'll be maintaining it, but in a single slash, it will be maintained. So, I hope… how many of you got the core idea of
Krish NAik: the chunking that I have done, where I've used the accumulator skate and the flusher state.
Krish NAik: For each chunk, Every chunk will be maintaining that accumulator and flush.
Krish NAik: Because little bit this chunking approach is not…
Krish NAik: Conventional for beginners, but once you start working with, then you really will understand.
Krish NAik: And a few things here, a level of optimization, because I feel that the only con with this particular implementation, that you have to work on Python-level optimization.
Krish NAik: Right now, I'm using a lot of for loops and for loops, guys, but later on, you have to work a little bit with yield. How many of you know about yield for better memory?
Krish NAik: Optimization. Anybody else? I think, yield?
Krish NAik: Because right now, if I have a very long page, let's take 300 pages of PDF, my RAM will be full, because it's a single pass operation, guys.
Krish NAik: In that case, I have to do the Python optimization, where every time I won't be going through everything. So, page by page, I'll be keeping it through generators. Yes, the core idea is using generators, so that's why I'll be, changing few things with respect to
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm telling, what is the con side of this implementation when you try to do in a single pass?
Krish NAik: Yes, the input is actually from the JSON.
Krish NAik: that you have.
Krish NAik: And if you look into, like, junker.py is actually, like, is coming from the post processor. If you look into this post processor file, this is actually the…
Krish NAik: JSON. Okay, if you look into import JSON, so this is the file from where we are actually converting the JSON into Markdown, but we are actually saving the results also.
Krish NAik: So, from here, we are getting that element type, that I am using it here. Element, like, all the elements from the JSON that will be coming in. So, yes, that is correct, Mother.
Krish NAik: But right now…
Krish NAik: This is the high-level chunking. Now, this is completely a custom chunker. According to your use case, just always think about having state management in your chunking, because I feel that it's really important.
Krish NAik: and the optimization according to the size of the PDFs. If you're really working with big, big PDFs, like.
Krish NAik: more than 50MB of PDFs. In that case, yes, optimizations, that can be done with respect to Python generators.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, the post-processor file, this is the simple file through which I'm doing the transformation from JSON to Markdown. So here, I have done multiple labels, you can see assemble, markdown. These are the lists of transformation criterias that I have added it.
Krish NAik: Okay, a few things I have added it. So, completely, the rendered type is not exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Because you can add more and more information. If you fail, and if you look into the markdown file right now, where is the markdown, markdown, markdown file? It's in the
Krish NAik: output.
Krish NAik: Any idea on with all these optimizations? It totally depends upon your solution. This is not retrieval-level accuracy of machine, neither generation level. This is your data integration phase part.
Krish NAik: Can we see around 90%?
Krish NAik: Again, like, in which phase in the pipeline are you talking about 90%?
Krish NAik: Okay, so the core purpose of, post-processor is convert your JSON file into a Markdown file, and finally save that to a JSON file. Similarly, you'll be having a function save to markdown files.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see, logger.info, set markdown to MD5Path. This file is just getting that JSON value, converting that JSON into a custom markdown transformation map that I have provided, and it will be saving that file. Other than that, there is no,
Krish NAik: I can say main purpose of using this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, now… Core part with respect to logging, config, okay, post-processor. There is pipeline.py.
Krish NAik: Now, this pipeline.py that I have, are you using MITRE? No, no, no, no. I am not using markdown input. I am using the JSON. JSONs are more important to me.
Krish NAik: Markdown, I'm just showing you because it is easier for visualization for your own eyes.
Krish NAik: I'm not creating the Markdown file. Sorry, it means that I'm not using the markdown file anywhere. I'm just saving it.
Krish NAik: Because working with JSON files is much easier.
Krish NAik: If you have the JSON, because it's from JSON, I'm converting it into a mat.
Krish NAik: So, why use Markdown?
Krish NAik: Because then, really, the quality of the markdown needs to be really looked into. If you really look here, I'm just showing you the way that I have created with respect to those.
Krish NAik: So now, few things. Now, here it created a table. I'm giving a simple example. Do you think that it was a table?
Krish NAik: Just tell me, guys. I think everybody has gone through the Docklink technical report.
Krish NAik: Do you think that in the first phase, it was a table?
Krish NAik: there was no table, so that's why. It's only for rendering part that I have kept.
Krish NAik: Okay, because really, the quality of the render, I feel that, I have done a bare minimum task, and… but again, in some cases, it's correct, in some cases, it's wrong. So, really, the quality of that markdown is not good. So, I'm not using the markdown file anymore. I am only using the JSON.
Krish NAik: Because my transformation map is not really that up to the map.
Krish NAik: I really need to work much more on that.
Krish NAik: Perfect, now…
Krish NAik: Oh… Chunker, config, logging, okay. Now, as I was talking about, only one file is remaining.
Krish NAik: It's 11, I think people are telling about breaks, alright? Let's take a 10-minute break, and then we'll come back.
Krish NAik: You can use TUNE. Tune is, again, see, Tune is such a project, again.
Krish NAik: got hyped, but again, I feel that adoption is less.
Krish NAik: You can use tool.
Krish NAik: to a certain level, but again, I didn't feel that Tune is a very successful project.
Krish NAik: And I'm seeing a lot of people using it in their own production pipeline. But you can use tooth, there is no issue with it.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me start a 10-minute timer, and I think then we'll be back.
Krish NAik: Timer, timer, timer, where is that block?
Krish NAik: Art defense.
Krish NAik: Oh, great, guys.
Krish NAik: Mealtime, anything that you need to…
Krish NAik: Ask me, and let me know in chat.
Krish NAik: Some are, I can say. JSON files are better, much more, like.
Krish NAik: Lightweight visors compared to Markdown fights.
Krish NAik: For visualization also, Murthasa, I'm using the JSON file. I am not using Markdown file anywhere.
Krish NAik: It's just, I've rendered one output.
Krish NAik: Everywhere I've used JSOM.
Krish NAik: Aniroth is asking, sir, if we don't have images and we have not created JSON files still document our channel.
Krish NAik: Yes, it is good in that case also. There is no issue. Compared to, 1K plus pages.
Krish NAik: there you have to do optimizations, like, in a PDF, if you have 1,000 pages, really, then you can use document versus chunking versus use generators.
Krish NAik: Rather than loading entirely in one shot, in that case.
Krish NAik: What do you think of… yes, page index is good, I think. This Thursday, I'll be talking about
Krish NAik: AK, like, it totally depends upon the type of documents, SK.
Krish NAik: I don't feel that everywhere it is to be used.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, it creates a tree-based approach.
Krish NAik: So, yes, in some cases it's good, where you feel that there is some linking.
Krish NAik: You… Your document has such type of meaning.
Krish NAik: If your document where the semantics are different, in that case, not really so much available.
Krish NAik: Especially rag is spelling in financial documents.
Krish NAik: Financial documents, yes, it will work, but again, RAG works on financial documents also. Okay, it depends, like, what is the type of…
Krish NAik: implementation that has been done. Vectorless rag on everything.
Krish NAik: So, it's on a safer side, but again, right now.
Krish NAik: Not purely open source, I can say.
Krish NAik: The structure in the document is maintained, if you have a TOC, everything in detail.
Krish NAik: then that makes sense. If you don't have a structure in your document, financial documents, or any type of documents, I feel that for financial documents, this approach is better, tree-based approach.
Krish NAik: Vectorless approach, you can try, but the poor thing that you can do your initial research with a subset of your data.
Krish NAik: Because I calculated for financial documents the…
Krish NAik: Accuracy as compared to the traditional rack is… can be hard. But again, what is your pipeline consist in the core rack?
Krish NAik: Before moving to Vectorless RAM, my idea is that
Krish NAik: Have you tried everything or not? If you have not tried everything, Then it becomes,
Krish NAik: For all your hallucinations, I've already showed, you can… Use very specific hallucination groups.
Krish NAik: Self-suggesting routes and database for improvement.
Krish NAik: In day one, those things cannot be with respect to time those appointments come.
Krish NAik: From day one. You can go with vectorless RAG, I can say that, starting, because a normal RAG implementation will take more time.
Krish NAik: Poor financial wisdom.
Krish NAik: Try out, I think this, Thursday I'll be talking about, page intent.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that, posting page intact, that is the other way around. Self-posting into your own environment, that will be at least cheaper as compared to using their Kim.
Krish NAik: their cloud with respect to time, will be much harder, so you can do the self-hosting of page index and keep it your own cloud info. That will be much cheaper, and the data also always stays in.
Krish NAik: That's it. So, try that, part.
Krish NAik: Because there, with respect to tree-based retrieval techniques, you can add a reasoning loop also. In that way, the hallucinations will be towards the lower side.
Krish NAik: on Thursday, then, I will be picking up something like an
Krish NAik: I think, I can get free data from the HCC API from there. I will show one.
Krish NAik: usefuls.
Krish NAik: That was the only thing that I, worry about if your document has a proper structure.
Krish NAik: TOC is their numbered section, chapters, table of contents. In that case, page index…
Krish NAik: is better. But if you have a corpus, just like NLP corpus.
Krish NAik: In that case, it is not.
Krish NAik: So always take that particular decision that you have the document structure or a normal compass.
Krish NAik: Can you try SEC filings? Alright, I will take that exam.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm gonna make a desktop.
Krish NAik: Bullshit.
Krish NAik: And generally, in the field of banking, finance, I feel that Explainability is also better with respect to
Krish NAik: vector-less rack, because there you can actually show the entire node information. In that way, the explainability is better, whereas showing some, simple, dense numbers, like similarity scores.
Krish NAik: I mean, debugging is a little bit tougher for non-technical people.
Krish NAik: So… so, sorry, for, yes, non-technical people. So, in that way, I feel with respect to the explanative of your solution, it makes much more sense.
Krish NAik: So, few things are there. So, financial document, yes, it's good, but always remember.
Krish NAik: That, the cost of the solution will be a little bit higher.
Krish NAik: Because if you add a reasoning loop.
Krish NAik: for every node. In that case, for every of your node, a separate LLM call will be built.
Krish NAik: If your node is very, very long, like node and multi-node, with nested noding in that case.
Krish NAik: the cost of the solution increases, but again, the chances of hallucination will be very minimal. That's fine.
Krish NAik: Explain… I'm talking about the explainability of your solution becomes better.
Krish NAik: Because there you can actually show that modem formation.
Krish NAik: That, from this page, this node, and that.
Krish NAik: I'll be showing you, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think I can stop sharing.
Krish NAik: All right, now, let's get back, to our core discussion. I think, one…
Krish NAik: file. Once… I think this is the last poor pipeline.file I have, then I'll be coming to our main API folder.
Krish NAik: So here, the main, document parsing pipeline, so where initially.
Krish NAik: We are, looking into our get settings from your actual config.py file. Post-processing things, I am importing, assemble, markdown, and save to JSON.
Krish NAik: Counting the total number of PDFs. Now, this is simple utility, which is available under the details folder. Okay, so under the YouTube PDFs, like, def, PDF, page to image.
Krish NAik: If you want to do a conversion in that case, count the PDF number of pages, validate the input file. Okay, so simple file not found, so 3 simple functions that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Can anybody tell me, like, a PDF page to image, in which condition it will be much more helpful? Because I was actually usually planning for
Krish NAik: Pool Pali integration also. Later on, I removed that, but for that particular integration, this PDF page changed. That was the main purpose.
Krish NAik: All right, so let's get back to our pipeline.py. Alright, so here, settings, few things from our post-processing. Okay, assemble markdown and save to JSON.
Krish NAik: Now, trying the GLM was here.
Krish NAik: Initializing is the list of past elements that I'll be having, having one is a label text.
Krish NAik: Then comes your bounding box, the scoring, the reading order.
Krish NAik: Now, this is one class data limiting, so a single detected and recognized document element. Now, this output type will be coming from your PP detection layout. Then come page results, so parsing result from a single document page.
Krish NAik: So this, page result class, I'll be using it in structure of app chunking.
Krish NAik: Then, another parse result. So, this is a page result, and this is a parse result, the complete parsing result for a document. Now, this is for your entire document, which will be used by, document interaction.
Krish NAik: So, here you have your, source file.
Krish NAik: Guys, I got disconnected, it looks like, lost it.
Krish NAik: Just read, I think there is some issue… With respect to the…
Krish NAik: I will add one panelist. Anybody just raise your hand?
Krish NAik: I will add one panelist, because if I get disconnected, then again, I can connect it. Just be sure you are in the meeting, okay? I'm adding Rajot.
Krish NAik: Just a little bit, let's have a check.
Krish NAik: Internet got…
Krish NAik: The internet is fine.
Krish NAik: We do have a backup one, but this is Xbox, I don't need to…
Krish NAik: All right, let's get back. Okay, so from the output of the layout detection model, I am trying to create that page result. So, you can see this is the list of page results that I'll be accumulating in one place. And now, from here, the final element, like, that I'll be using it during the chunking phase.
Krish NAik: Then comes your, raw page information, the actual JSON file, import that you have. So that's why, from here I am accessing the JSON underscore resign. Okay, so this is the return type from the GLM.
Krish NAik: Was he at SD?
Krish NAik: Now, the full, markdown file, now this particular information is also available from the GLMC, GLM OCR SDK, so that's why, through this particular variable, I can access the full results.
Krish NAik: So that's why I created a custom map, because this particular information, as it was thrown by the model, I can use it.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, for, page index, and we are iterating over the elements from the layout detection for every page that I have.
Krish NAik: Now, inside the raw page, raw page means in the raw page, you will be having all the attribute types, the JSON attribute types. Then, I'm looping over every page by page, so initially the index starts with 0, so the first page, second page, in that way, I'll be looping over.
Krish NAik: Now, from raw underscore EL in raw elements, now, from here, I'll be accessing the nested elements
Krish NAik: Of the JSON, because directly inside one JSON file, I don't have. It's pretty much a nested structure. If you look into here, the final output type of the JSON that I have inside the OLAMA folder, you'll understand the core JSON structure.
Krish NAik: So, I think this is the core JSON structure that we have. It's pretty much necessary structure, where I have the core attributes, the native level, now this is the actual level, which is being thrown from the LED detection one.
Krish NAik: So I'm parsing over the entire JSON file, and I'm creating that page parse results. Okay, so finally, the total number of elephants in each page, so that's why for 15 pages, the final result that I'm creating, and I'm saving it into a JSON file.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I have selected the output directory as this one.
Krish NAik: Something is happening today, really, I'm not sure… The internet is fine…
Krish NAik: Goodbye, Halloween.
Krish NAik: Yes, I got Dishi again. Yeah, I know, Rajat, you are there, fine. That's the one panelist I needed. Right. Now, this is a core JSON file that finally I am saving it, and this information, actually, I'm going to save it
Krish NAik: In production, always save this file. Always understand.
Krish NAik: Now, your file, your actual PDF that was uploaded.
Krish NAik: Then comes your docklink, report, the actual, I can say, your, JSON file or the Markdown file,
Krish NAik: that information with the chunks.json. So, this is a chunk.json information that I'm actually sharing it, because this chunk.json actually helps you to do a lot of verification. Your initial chunk, which is archive, technical report, this type of information is coming. You can see some tables that's there.
Krish NAik: there is a table tag, so I can say that that author names and everything that came inside that single one. Now, what is the chunk ID? Doclingreport.pdf.
Krish NAik: that I have kept it, and underscore zero.
Krish NAik: Why underscore zero, guys? This is the first chunk. Then if you look into the second chunk, Underscore 1.
Krish NAik: Then, underscore 2.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, in the next page.
Krish NAik: your page number changed. So, in that particular page, you have rich chart.
Krish NAik: Again, the first channel.
Krish NAik: That's why indexing with zero. Then again, in the second page, you have your second chunk. I hope everybody is understanding how the chunking ID, that is getting created. In that way, it becomes easier for you to analyze at any point of time. Okay, now this chunk is from the second page.
Krish NAik: Okay, from the second page, the second chunk that you have.
Krish NAik: So, in that way, I'm maintaining the chunk order also.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's get back to our pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, so finally, saving out the files inside your core output folder. Now, this is a core document parser class that I have, which I'll be calling it from our FastAPI also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so initializing the JLM OCR file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just checking for whether going through the OLAMA mode, or going through the secret, or the API mode version. DevP parse file, once the file entire, the parsing is done, so initially we are looking for the file is available or not.
Krish NAik: If the file is available, we'll be looking into the settings, like, the core, parsing settings that I have. Okay, and then, I'm setting that always start with a page ID of 0, A with a total PGS minus number 1, and this logger.information, because
Krish NAik: ULAMA version that I have. ULAMA, by default, uses the PIMU PDF.
Krish NAik: So, if you are changing your PDF reading package, the number of pages will be different. Always understand that. The total number of pages, every package has their own. Some starts with zero.
Krish NAik: Some starts with 1, so you have to maintain that order. So, according to the package, always decide that this is your page counting logic, according to the reader package that you have used.
Krish NAik: Now, once I have done it, now parse result from SDK. So, if you look into, now I'm going back to the mean from SDK results that I am actually getting it. I'm using that.
Krish NAik: into my core part file.
Krish NAik: once this particular parsing is successfully done, I'm getting, and I am saving all the results in one page. So the total number of pages that have been parsed, we'll be getting that into the logger.
Krish NAik: And now this is parse batch. When you are parsing multiple files in one shot, in that case, so if you want to parse an entire directory with all the PDFs, then you can actually use this function of parseUnderScore batch. So in our application, we have that also.
Krish NAik: I've not kept a separate route for that, but you can create a separate FastAPI route for this particular implementation also.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's get back here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a corepipeline.py.
Krish NAik: And now, let's get back to our API folder. Now, I will start discussing a little bit about the APIs. So, inside your doc parser, the first file, one is the API folder. Let's start with the API folder. So, how many routes we have in our application? So, the generateRoute.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the LLM generation. It means that your entire pipeline of your query, then retrieval, re-ranking, everything, the parameters are there. Based on that, if you make re-ranking 2 or 12, based on that, you will be getting the output.
Krish NAik: Now, one thing, a bad approach that I have taken in the implementation, I have not maintained a prompts.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, going forward, we'll be maintaining a prompt.py also. What about the prompts that I am using?
Krish NAik: Okay, it's a good practice to maintain it in a separate file, rather than every time hard-coding it in a single
Krish NAik: Peace or place.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I feel that, with,
Krish NAik: Auto-research, just like the implementation has shown, I can actually improve my system prompts also. Pretty much recursive improvements based on the metrics that I have defined.
Krish NAik: Do you want to maintain a prompt. prompts.py?
Krish NAik: I want to maintain. Inside that, there will be a variable. I'll be just importing that variable, Matesh.
Krish NAik: That variable will be multi-line,
Krish NAik: I hope you get that. You don't need a markdown file.
Krish NAik: You can keep it through… access it through a PY file. Just access the variables.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, here I have kept it, that for our generation, you are a precise document assistant. Now, if you remember.
Krish NAik: During the generation phase, you can override this default system prompt.
Krish NAik: How many of you remembered that?
Krish NAik: In our API, I told you, you can pass your own custom prompt also.
Krish NAik: So, always remember that we have given that particular option.
Krish NAik: Now, building the user context, which is the context assembly part. So, returns a plain string when no candidates carry image underscore base64 text-only path, identical to previous, returns a multimodal content list.
Krish NAik: When at least one visual chunk has image 64 populated with it. Interleving the context text with the inline Base64 image block. Now, initially, whenever you are building the context assembly phase, it means that you have 7 charts.
Krish NAik: or 5 chance. The final number of chunks, let's take from your iterable, or from your render. Now, the main part is, you need to concatenate all those sums.
Krish NAik: But if you have that image information, then you need to, pass that image information to GPT-4 also.
Krish NAik: So that GPT-40 can actually look into the image base 64, the actual information.
Krish NAik: So, for our visual chunks, for C, if I have the base64 value, then only it can send it. If not, then the context will be pretty much normal. Okay, so pretty much normal context. Otherwise, it will be added, the visual chunk will be added into your original context assembly.
Krish NAik: Then finally, whatever the query that you will be asking it, the core content, so the final you can see, for seeing visual jump.
Krish NAik: this is the final, context assembly, I can say. What is the type of modality for that? Because I am telling that I am passing base64 for only two conditions, okay? The modality, if it is, basically the visual phase, or it's a visual chunk, I can say.
Krish NAik: What is the meaning of a visual chunk? A chunk which has a basic food.
Krish NAik: It is a simple mean.
Krish NAik: And that base64 information, I'll be passing it to the LLM during the generation phase.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I need to attach the base64 into the context assembly, and then pass it for our final generation.
Krish NAik: So, I'm appending that.
Krish NAik: into the context assembly, so content.append, image URL with the poor base.64 information, guys.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where I'm adding that information and passing it to your final element. Now, these are your simple route settings, so router.post, this is a post call, dev generate, embed query, re-ranking candidates true or false.
Krish NAik: Building the context strain top-end chunks, and finally call your GPT-40 and return the answer plus source chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is where I'm calculating the time, also the response time, of the entire call, so that's why I'm used per counter here.
Krish NAik: And finally, raising some exception, if I'm getting some exception, the total number of candidates are basically the total number of sources which have been used for generating your final answer.
Krish NAik: Rajat is asking what we received, the base64, form user as a form, front-end application.
Krish NAik: You can render the base XD.
Krish NAik: Also, there is no issues in there. In the front end, you can render it also.
Krish NAik: In that way, the explainability of your solution becomes better. If you have the V64, you should always render it in your front-end.
Krish NAik: If it is a multimodal jump, it means that if it's actually an image. For your text, it doesn't matter so much.
Krish NAik: All right, now, the different type of context parts where you have
Krish NAik: The text, the table data, in that case, you can just…
Krish NAik: keep everything inside the context underscore part, appending every type of information. Okay, and here I have kept it very separately for a table, because for table, if you, remember.
Krish NAik: I was maintaining that what will be the total number of input chunks for the table, and the total number of, sorry, not chunks, input tokens and output tokens.
Krish NAik: I've kept it as, like, 2,000. If you feel that that number of tables is bigger, please do have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so LLM generation sees the full table data, and not just the retrieval-based summary. So in that case, I can say the LLM will know the actual information, and even if you're doing the captioning, that particular information will come. So I feel that it's a better way
Krish NAik: Use captions, use the original image. The final generation will be much more better.
Krish NAik: Now, if request.system now, this is the variable that I'm accepting it from the front end, from the Swagger UI. If you are not passing anything, then the default system prompt will be activated. Then comes, I am calling the chat open AI, and there I am passing the system prompt.
Krish NAik: building the final user content, where I'm passing the rack query with the total number of candidates, which have been received in the
Krish NAik: Retrieval fields.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from there, I am finally generating the answer. And this is the main structure of the chunk result, which I have defined in my schemas.py, that will be returned, okay? And the final generate response class, this is how it looks like. So this is the chunk.
Krish NAik: Because this is every… how every chunk has been saved into the vector table with all the attributes, and this is the schema for your generate response, where you have your actual query, where you have your answer, where you have your sources, the total number of candidates, how many sources have been used, and the final latency for that request call.
Krish NAik: Okay, or the final response time that you'll have.
Krish NAik: Similarly, you have your health. Health is nothing. It's simply, like, checking whether the OpenAI is available, whether your quadrant is available. Okay, two major checks are there. One is your quadrant and OpenAI. If they are available, you are good to go with your application. So, two simple health checks that I have added.
Krish NAik: You can increase the number of parallel API workers on your room. Right now, I've kept the number of API workers for FastAPI as 1. Going forward, if you need more number of concurrency, you can increase it to 8. Just be sure you are using a compute-optimized instance, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, you need more RAM in that case.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes your, this is the ingestion phase.
Krish NAik: ingest.py, this is a document ingestion. Okay, so here, what are the poor things? First of all, your poor, fast API, API router, file form, even, I think, here I was uploading the PDF also, so multi-part will also come into the picture.
Krish NAik: I'm getting my quadrant. So, in from Quadrant, I've taken the BM25 implementation, and Quadrant also have the default hybrid search. So, I've taken directly the implementations from the Quadrant package, rather than using Langchain, because that doesn't make sense to use LangChain or using Llama Index. Why to use such AV packages?
Krish NAik: Now, first, from the dependencies, get embedded tip, get client. These are, a few health checks if you really look into. Okay, now, three things with respect to the, I'm maintaining the cache also for OpenAI client.
Krish NAik: Okay, for your quadrant score, for your base lead ranker selection, okay, and for your base embedder.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that which embedding model, which re-ranking model, which quadrant. That's why I maintained the LRU catcher. Later on, you can make, because LRU catcher is…
Krish NAik: A bare minimum implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, I feel that later on you can upgrade it, and you can use better catching operations out there. But for now, simple dependencies.
Krish NAik: Now, these, that I am checking it. It means that these are the default values that I want to go with. Then comes, importing my schema models.
Krish NAik: my… every request has two things, the request and the response model. So, for ingestion, what is the request model, what is the response model that I am importing? Now, from your chunker, import chunk, and I'm using the document-aware chunking, if you want to change
Krish NAik: Page by page, then change it to structure-aware Chunking also.
Krish NAik: Getting the default settings then comes from your embedder, embed chunks. Now, this is where your vector store will be initialized, so I think your vector store is inside the ingestion pool. So, this is where your actual vector store.
Krish NAik: Enrich jumps is there, so this is from your image captioner. So let's try to go inside each file now. So let's start with embed charms.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the embedded.py. So, what will happen in your embedding phase?
Krish NAik: So, first of all, your main, I convert everything to lowercase, then comes embed text. So, once you have your code text from the chance, then only you can
Krish NAik: are initialized here.
Krish NAik: Embedding operation.
Krish NAik: So here, I'm using TextEmbitting 3. Now, this is the default setting, which can be overwritten through your,
Krish NAik: env file, so you can pass… so this is the default parameters dimension. What is the batch size? Now, batch size I have taken, how much? Which is 100.
Krish NAik: Always remember that, generally, I've seen that 100, it works, but don't think about if you pass 500 or 1,000, it will work.
Krish NAik: Always respect the API.
Krish NAik: At least have 2 seconds of sleep, or 3 seconds of sleep whenever you are working with higher bed cycles.
Krish NAik: Okay, so every vector databases do have that particular batch size, so please do have a check on the documentation as per the usage statue.
Krish NAik: Okay, so batch size for OpenEmbed, so in one shot, I know that multiple embeddings that I can pass it, 100 chunks, fine. Embed the text using the OpenAI.
Krish NAik: text, client, embedding model dimensions, return type, everything within a list, I am getting that. Okay, so all embeddings, I am extending that to every item embeddings, and I am retaining that. So this is the main embeddings which are ready, which needs to be fed into that.
Krish NAik: your, vector store. Now, this is purely what type of embedding? This is dense embedding. Now comes your VM25 implementation from Quadrant that I have taken it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you, look into…
Krish NAik: Now, how many of you… okay, now this implementation is based on BM25 sparse.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a little bit each sparse vector with an unique hashing operation that I have kept it. Okay, now I will say that this is not pure BM25. This is a lightweight, modified version of BM25.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can change it with the original version.
Krish NAik: of BM25 by installing the Okapi BM25 package, but I have taken a modified version of BM2, so it's exactly the size of the sparse vector, will be smaller.
Krish NAik: As compared to that, bigger size, where you have, like, 20,000, 30,000, 40,000 dimension size. Why want to little bit optimize on that sparse vector, so I have used a smaller variant.
Krish NAik: Okay, in this way, I can say the size, the feature size of your vectors will be towards the lower side, as directly using Okapi BM25 algorithm.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Segments are basically, pointed data, that we do refer.
Krish NAik: Well, let me turn out,
Krish NAik: core… usually the modality segments that I have, there also I've kept it in segmented basis.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm just creating a few, base embedder classes, through which I'll be later using it. So, one is the base embedder. Inside the base embedder, I've kept two different classes. Now, this is here my main class.
Krish NAik: Now, this is an abstract method, and later on, I'm just following that base class, so simply inheriting the properties of the base embedder, and I have done the implementation of OpenAI. Similarly, I have a class with respect to the Gemini embedder also.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want to use that, so a simple… your main base class on top of that, two separate implementations, which I can use it through the base embedded class.
Krish NAik: If you want to use the Gemini embedding, two previews, here also I was getting good results, but I feel that, yes, you can use it.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the main, async version. Now, if you look into this is the core embedded part, but here also I feel that, I, was testing with higher batch sizes.
Krish NAik: But I feel that OpenAI is better as compared to Gemini.
Krish NAik: I felt that, always using Android.
Krish NAik: you have to reduce the number of dash size here. Whenever, if you are working with Gemini, reduce it to 50, 40, it works better. 100, it works for one document. In the second document, I feel that, though it's a free version, I can say.
Krish NAik: Entire one, I was getting there.
Krish NAik: If you are in enterprise, then you won't be getting the error, but I felt that entire one and entire two subscriptions, that is a problem.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, what are the core base embedder providers, OpenAI and the Gemini. So you can use, actually, your base embedder class, and you can overwrite the properties on it.
Krish NAik: Do you have any alternatives to async your package?
Krish NAik: Generally, asynchio package, I feel that in…
Krish NAik: Jupyter Notebooks, I require it. In my core, I can say, application, you can use asyncure
Krish NAik: A few modified versions are there, but I feel that you need to always work a little bit on the customization of your issues.
Krish NAik: Because what are functions that you want to make async? Every function doesn't need to be async.
Krish NAik: In your application, what needs to be asynchronous, you need to work on that. Because where the latency is much more higher, those types of functions make sense much more to make them asynchronous, as compared to where if the response time is very, very less.
Krish NAik: But, in production, I try to use at least more than 70% of my functions as asynchronous.
Krish NAik: And I feel that it's a better approach, but not everything.
Krish NAik: I make it.
Krish NAik: Asynchronous are good, but little bit, downside, I feel.
Krish NAik: with respect to if I'm working with operations where the latency is very, very high, and it is actually dependent on the output. It means that, let's take the example of layout detection. It might take, 1 minute or 2 minutes.
Krish NAik: Okay, in that case, you cannot actually initiate the rest of the pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I feel that in those cases, it makes much more sense that way.
Krish NAik: So, sir, generation fields meets async.
Krish NAik: It totally depends. In the generation part, you can use async, I don't feel, because you already have your, core output, retrieval and other things.
Krish NAik: Over here, you can use async, no problem, because your retrieval will never take too much high time, neither your re-ranking will take so much high time. The highest time in a rank pipeline is the document ingestion pipeline. Always remember that.
Krish NAik: The more the complex… Pipeline that you have for your documentation, Hart are time minutes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so finally comes your embedding the chunks. So once the embedding is done, so the final return type of every chunk, it becomes dense and vectors. Now, this value, I'll be pushing it to our vector store here.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's go to Enrich chunks. Enrich chunks is the image captioning part, I will come to this, but before that, let's talk a little bit our, vector stories.
Krish NAik: Now, if you look into, in this particular vector store, I have taken quadrant client package, I told you, the poor input that I have taken. Now, here, sparse vectors, sparse vector params.
Krish NAik: 3-page point struct, HNSW config. Now, the core embedding that I was saving it, so I've taken the HNSW embedding type, because it is highly optimized, I feel that, and the… I can say…
Krish NAik: The response time is also better for HNSW configuration.
Krish NAik: Okay, now comes your Fusion Query. Now, this is basically the hybrid search implementation, so using Fusion and Fusion Query, you can implement… you do the implementation of hybrid search very, very quickly, rather than going through the Langshan or the Lama Index mode.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, ingestion embedder, base embedder, and compute the sparse vector. So, from there, I'm getting my main embeddings that I'll be getting from my OpenAI, then comes the compute sparse vectors that I'll be getting it from the BM25 implementation that I have done.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes class document quadrant store, initialize. So, let's check for the quadrant API key, whether localhost or that. Based on that, please select an async quadrant client that I have. Then comes creating the collection.
Krish NAik: So, if the collection already exists based on the parameter, you can overwrite also, so that particular condition is also there. So, you will be getting logger.info, creating the collection.
Krish NAik: Or overriding the collection based on that. Now, sparse vectors, so here, the sparse vector, params. Now, this is how, in Quadrant, you can do a sparse vector ingestion inside a collection.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because in my disk, I don't want to save it, I want to save it directly into the cloud, so that's why on disk physical to false. If you want to save it in local, in that case, you can use the on-disk physical to true.
Krish NAik: Now, Viraj is asking, okay, OPIC launched,
Krish NAik: No, Opicost only. I have not used Oli yet, Matesh.
Krish NAik: Raj is asking in one of my presenters, quadrants with 8 segments, in the hour, represent the quadrant with only 4 segments.
Krish NAik: I really need to see you on that.
Krish NAik: Because generally, after Dockerization, it should not happen that the number of segments change. It will always remain the same.
Krish NAik: Andar, Viraj, what about the number of points?
Krish NAik: Here's the number of points also changing.
Krish NAik: You can let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine. Now, this is the part where I'm creating the collection. After that, deleting the collection for that also I have. But I have not, I think there is a separate route also to delete the collection also.
Krish NAik: Then comes upsetting the chunkdown. This is the main place where we are actually uploading the dense embeddings and the sparse vectors both into the vector DB. So here, quadrant DB,
Krish NAik: batch size that I'm maintaining is 64. So, for the embedding generation phase, I use a batch size of 100, and right now, for your uploading, I'm maintaining a batch size of 64.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I know that, okay, in one shot, I can send 64 chunks. This is a better approach here. Please do test out with higher numbers. I feel that you can push it till 256. From 256, I started getting errors, so you can let me know based on your experiments.
Krish NAik: Then there is some issue, Viraj, if the number of points are getting changed.
Krish NAik: All right, now, comes upset, chunking. So, from here, if the length of the chunks is not equal to length of the embeddings, or the length of the chunks is not the length of the… now, in this, so simply an error, because
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands this condition always needs to be true, yes or no.
Krish NAik: This is a simple condition. The number of chunks has to be equal to the number of emittings, yes or no? That's why a simple, conditional check that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Then comes your name, payload that needs to be sent. So, this is how your chunk looks like. So if you look into, this is the actual chunk schema. So, this is the same payload that I am sending it to the collection in the cloud to be saved out to your Docker.
Krish NAik: So, point.append, in that way, each chunk that I'll be appending, so each chunk is basically a point, point struct, and based on that, a unique struct, a unique ID for every point that I am attaching it. To the vector, I am passing the text tense.
Krish NAik: and the BM25 sparse reson. And this is the final payload that I am sending it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, I'm doing the append operation. Initially started with 0. Okay, so step by step, we will be looping over all the points, and we'll be maintaining the batch size, so in one shot, I noted 64 batches of, chunks that can be, sent into the, quadrant.
Krish NAik: Alright, finally, now, if you look into in the vector store only, I have done the implementation of search.
Krish NAik: I've not created a separate file, but if you are doing an implementation, please keep your search
Krish NAik: In a different file.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that, though it is a vector store operation, such.
Krish NAik: you should keep it, because later on, if you feel that I don't want to use hybrid search, I want to use a different type of search. For example, if you want to add knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: And later on, you want to bring the implementation of hybrid search with your knowledge graph. In that case.
Krish NAik: only using the vector store, so keep this implementation in a separate. Now, this, search is basically an hybrid search implementation from, Quotent that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so hybrid dense plus sparse vectors with RRF fusion. Now, you can use RSS and RRF, both are available in quadrant, and I think one more is available. Something like TBSF,
Krish NAik: That particular fusion also, you can have a check.
Krish NAik: Now, initially, query tense, wait a better, first of all, we will initially, similarly, both the, query, so one for your dense, one for your sparse, that needs to be generated.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody agrees on that. Your query needs to be converted into vectors, so that is the thing that we are doing, one for tens, one for sparks.
Krish NAik: And then, query filter is equal to none, give filter underscore modality is none. Now, this is a parameter through swagger invite that I was passing. If you have that, now this is a simple metadata filtration condition that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: If you want to change, simply you know that, yes, it is possible, don't use it. Then, by default, it will query the points, and there you'll be passing your
Krish NAik: both the queries that you have, your tense, as well as your pass, and based on that, you'll be getting your top result. So here, I've taken top K into 2. It means that whatever the top K value that you are selecting, so total, you always get the double opt-in.
Krish NAik: Query type, Fusion Query, and here I have selected very specifically RRF.
Krish NAik: Please play on this particular parameters. Limit is equal to topK.
Krish NAik: And, with payload is equal to true, always use the payload during that, because we need that chunk-based information. It actually helps us.
Krish NAik: Now comes, query filter. Now, if you are actually passing any… because right now, the query filter is equal to none, so here also it will be none.
Krish NAik: And then, finally, the payload will be returned. It means that the number of chunks that are being retrieved will be, returned from the quadrant vectors.
Krish NAik: This is the high-level implementation.
Krish NAik: So, I think, Okay, now this is the… I think this is the routes part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so embedder, let's talk about, little bit about image captionerals, because I think this is the only other module where something new has been kept. Okay, now, let's talk about how to generate captions. Guys, please think about it.
Krish NAik: Whenever I'm talking about an operation of image captioning, how you can generate that.
Krish NAik: So here, what I have done, I know that I have the base64, or simply, like, I can use something like PDF to page also, and that way also, I can create it. For every page also, I can create a base64.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I have given few of the image-based dimensions whenever you are doing that, image
Krish NAik: like, page to PDF-based operations. Here, I have told that the minimum crop size should be 50 pixels.
Krish NAik: Now, how many of you know, like, 50 cross 50 pixels? It's very small.
Krish NAik: That is a mini… anything less than 50 that doesn't make sense in the field of computer vision.
Krish NAik: In computer vision, I know people have built facial recognition, systems on, very small, like 10 plus 10 pixels also.
Krish NAik: But later on, they have updated it to much higher pixels. So, older systems used to use very less pixels, but right now, I felt that, at least based on the PDF document, I know that I knew minimum, because 50 is very small. It doesn't make sense. So, that is the minimum crop size.
Krish NAik: That I have taken. You can make it bigger also, like, use close to 7080, so you can play with this one.
Krish NAik: So, table, maximum input characters for a table during the captioning, I've kept it, let's take 12,000. Maximum output tokens here, 2,000. Image, maximum tokens, I have kept it as 800. If you look into here, these are the limits that I have used it.
Krish NAik: Now, here I have used a simple image system prompt. You are a scientific figure analysis assistant for a document-readable system. First, classify the figure into one of these charts, like bar chart, line graph, scatter plot, pie charts, heat map, etc. Because I really have no idea what is the image about.
Krish NAik: Then comes charts, bar, okay, then comes diagram, flow charts, architectural diagrams, log diagram, network diagram.
Krish NAik: Photo, like, photograph, microscopy image, medical scan, screenshot, UI screenshot, code. In that way, now, this is a custom prompt, guys, that I've simply passed it. Then analyze this figure and respond it exactly in this format with no extra text. So, what type of image that I have?
Krish NAik: Then, based on that caption, 1 to 2 sentence description of what the figure shows overall. For semantic search. Now, this is the bottleneck.
Krish NAik: How many of you understand bottleneck?
Krish NAik: Now, this is a bottleneck. If you are only going ahead and you totally depend only on that particular caption.
Krish NAik: I hope I make 10th.
Krish NAik: Do you think that one or two sentences will help you to understand everything?
Krish NAik: Yes, limited context. If you have limited context, for sure, the quality of your semantic search will be lower. Here, you can keep it, like.
Krish NAik: Increase the number of sentences, add more and more things.
Krish NAik: Because I can say that if you are going with text-based approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, you should have more and more context here. The idea is to capture more context, so that's why here, I think,
Krish NAik: This is their caption, one to two sentences, and later on, if I go to…
Krish NAik: Multimodal rights are suit.
Krish NAik: initiative… With, respect to DocParser.
Krish NAik: In the edition phase, in the English captioning part.
Krish NAik: Perfect. So here also…
Krish NAik: So, if you look into the actual implementation, so here are also the captions. Now, always remember, in your core application, this is actually the con.
Krish NAik: I can say that, because really, I don't know that, I cannot say that, generate a caption of 512 tokens.
Krish NAik: I know that,
Krish NAik: when captions will be generated for image and tables, and those things, I'm keeping it as an atomic unit.
Krish NAik: it means that the original output of that OCR model, that will also be there. So, the chunk size will be really, really huge if you actually try to generate bigger captions.
Krish NAik: So always try to keep a trade-off, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I know that information will be coming, but with respect to your original image.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can keep, but just be sure with the number of tokens that you are playing. You can keep 4-5 sentences in a structured order, something like that.
Krish NAik: Now, here, detail for chart 4, diagram for photo. So, here I'm tool that describe the chart, all the pixel levels, you can keep legend details, data series name, key point, data, mean trade, so this is a simple prompt. Similarly, for diagrams, for two, screenshot and others.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a structured grouping and containment relationship, which component belongs to which group modules. Use dashes for sub-items.
Krish NAik: Taking another bill. Okay, now this is purely, I can say that.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is prompt, and really, like.
Krish NAik: Prompts, you need to really play with prompts, and then based on that, you have to analyze the final profile.
Krish NAik: Similarly, there is a table system prompt. Okay, now this is for tables.
Krish NAik: You are a scientific document analyst, saying, given a table for a research, you must respond with a valid JSON whom.
Krish NAik: No text outside the JSON object.
Krish NAik: Things step by step, count the number of columns, including the rule level. So here you can see, including row-level columns, including count the number of data rows, excluding the header row, reproduce the complete table in a markdown format.
Krish NAik: With the delimiters, include every row and every column. Do not summarize, skip, or truncate any information.
Krish NAik: Right, one to two sentence semantic again. This is a bottleneck.
Krish NAik: So, always try to understand what is the bottleneck whenever you are writing your prompts. Based on that, the response…
Krish NAik: will be there.
Krish NAik: So, now I've given a response structure, the number of columns, the number of rows, markdown, table, and summon.
Krish NAik: If I fail that, from the markdown table, I'll be getting most of the information.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, see, why are filters? Because I'm passing the text information that I got from
Krish NAik: the output of the, I can say parsing, as well as the original base64.
Krish NAik: So, rules for merged or spanning cells repeat the value across all affected. So, here are a few rules. You can add more and more rules. For empty cells, use underscore as a placeholder.
Krish NAik: Okay, use hyphen, I think. SK many pipe characters, so now this is the…
Krish NAik: AI-generated prompt that simply I used it. Similarly, you have a formula prompt and an algorithm prompt. Really, I've not worked on formula and algorithm a lot. I was working visually on tables and images.
Krish NAik: So, you can… because here I'm telling that, given a mathematical formula for equation in latex, respond in exactly in those formulas.
Krish NAik: So you can ask AI to generate, to generate the latex source.
Krish NAik: If you want. But I feel that saving the latex Doesn't make sense so much.
Krish NAik: Okay, but if you feel that, you can keep… use the latex. Similarly for algorithms that I…
Krish NAik: Now, these are response parses. Okay, so parse image responses, so whatever the response that will be coming, based on the structure that I've given, based on that, I'm much more focused on the caption part from… because this caption, I'll be adding it into the text field of the chart, so that's why this parse image response.
Krish NAik: Pass text response, so a very similar parsing operation for your image-based captions. Then comes parse table JSON response. Similarly, the table structure that I have gifted. So, whatever the output will be coming, based on that, I'll be always parsing the JSON responses.
Krish NAik: for the text responses, according to the, prompt structure that I have defined.
Krish NAik: Okay, so one separate function that I have kept it is validate table extraction, so I feel that this validation makes sense that check if the extracted table dimensions roughly match expectations. Now, again, this is not 100% correct validation.
Krish NAik: Here, I tell that, okay, 30% rough estimated one.
Krish NAik: Because really, I cannot say that 100% accuracy with respect to the LLM output.
Krish NAik: For 100% accuracy with respect to the parcel.
Krish NAik: Nobody can be 100% sure that both the things are correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, from the original markdown written table from the OCR, I'm just having a check. If not markdown table or the number of rows reported.
Krish NAik: In that case, return true. Nothing to validate against, if you don't have any data only.
Krish NAik: So, count, non-separated, non-empty rows in the extracted markdown. So, based on that, I have kept this particular logic. So, you should keep your own validations.
Krish NAik: Because really, what is being extracted
Krish NAik: Okay, and really, what is being generated? Okay, in that case, during the generation phase, you can. Because right now, this is much more from the captioning point of view, but I feel that you have two ways of doing the validation.
Krish NAik: Because when I'm doing the caption generation, then also I'm sending the information to GPT, and the other is the output of the GLM OCR. So in that way, two things that are coming. Even 70% of the things are common, I will say that you are good to go.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you always take a threshold of having a check on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, extract text from a judge and key terms from document. Now, this is get surrounding context. Generally, like, I feel that this is what does.
Krish NAik: context enhancement. When you try to actually get more context around your chunks in those cases, it is important. You can look up to two positions, the before and after the mean targeted chunk.
Krish NAik: In that way, the context enhancement works better. It was simple. Now, in this particular case, based on modality, you have to do the tricks back. So, CD will modality is equal to text.
Krish NAik: Now, why?
Krish NAik: Guys?
Krish NAik: Do you think that for image and tables, it matters?
Krish NAik: Those are atomic units, they doesn't matter. What matters to us is only, basically, the text chunks. But that's why two separate, loops that I have, one is your… the forward loop, one is your backward loop, you can always have a checkpoint.
Krish NAik: And finally, based on that, we are combining the information.
Krish NAik: Crop chunk to base 64. Now, this is the part where
Krish NAik: Actually, like, I need to do the cropping operation, and based on that, I'm generating the base 64. That I'll be passing it to the LLM for a better caption quality, because during the generation, fine, you are sending, and you are having the information of the,
Krish NAik: core, passes or output. But how to do the much more enrichment? So this is the enrichment thing, and how you are doing the enrichment?
Krish NAik: By actually getting the original base64 and passing it.
Krish NAik: to your main element. So, similarly, one for table, one for image, so that's why single, image enrichment that you have
Krish NAik: Similarly, table enrichment that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, in that way, you can enrich your chunks much more, if you feel that. I have only two things. Similarly, you can add enrichment for your formula and algorithms also.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, somehow, if the table extraction fails, so there is a retry trivial extraction happens, I was actually testing it, and in some cases, it failed, actually. But because of that, I kept a separate function. If, but in some cases, it failed, the idea is to retry it, okay?
Krish NAik: Then you can see enrich formula. So here, actually, I'm not passing the base64, guys. Okay. Then, similarly, you have enrich algorithm. Again, here, also, I'm not passing any Base64. So here, you can add these type of enrichment.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is all about the core enrichment of the chunks over here.
Krish NAik: You can, look into… this is the final enrichment function that looks like.
Krish NAik: So here, enrichment of all non-text charts.
Krish NAik: Because non-tech chunks will be… atomic chunks. Where it's chain chunks, it will be…
Krish NAik: non-atomic, okay. Or, there will be multiple subatomic units.
Krish NAik: So, image, structure type, caption details, structure detail, a vision call, vision calls means you'll be calling a multimodal LLM with surrounding document context for better understanding.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes table extraction, complete markdown, reproduction, plus semantic summary, JSON mode, formula, and detailed verbal description only, because this is a pretty much single text call, because from the
Krish NAik: when I'm hitting this, I am not passing the base64. So, the output, I know, it will be pretty much single text probably only, similarly for the algorithm ones.
Krish NAik: Now, for tables, chunk.caption, now this is the actual JSON value, which holds a full markdown table.
Krish NAik: Okay, and for images, chunk.caption, pulls the short 1-22 sentence caption.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, now, always remember that, so this is the bottleneck I am telling, so please have a check on this, how better you can
Krish NAik: more optimistic.
Krish NAik: Alright, finally, performing the enrichment of all the attributes for a document. Then, finally, checking the final enrichment step.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… here I'm calling the enrichment of the chunks. Now, this is a backward compatibility that I have adjusted, but I'm not using it anymore. Okay, so in the first use case, I didn't enrich the chunks, later on, I have done.
Krish NAik: Alright, now… And let's get to… Europe?
Krish NAik: I think, image captioner, this is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the retrieval, there is only the re-ranker, so let's talk about, as I told you, there are 4 re-ranking backends.
Krish NAik: Okay, one is the OpenAI. Okay, now this is a prompt-based implementation.
Krish NAik: Jinna, from here I am using MO. MO is the visual re-ranker-supported, I can say, re-ranking model.
Krish NAik: Then comes your VGM3. Now, this is a text only. It cannot handle visual data.
Krish NAik: Or, multimodal, okay, only text it can handle, then finally comes 3 below. Now, this, I have used it in the PIN3 branch.
Krish NAik: Now, here, I think I was working with OpenAI and Jenna much more.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here I have created a base re-ranker class, because we know what is the input to a ranker? Any type of re-ranking operation, what is the input and what is the output? I will say that in the input, I pass 20 chance. In the output, I am expecting 5 chance or 10 chance, yes or no?
Krish NAik: This is a simple, so here, def, rank, query, okay, because generally, most of the re-rankers use cross encoders, so you will be passing the total number of candidates. Based on that, you'll be getting the shortlisted candidates.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, this is the core class, the base re-ranker class. On top of that, I've taken the OpenAI re-ranker. So here, I told you this is a prompt-based approach, where I've taken a simple scaling-based.
Krish NAik: No, really, like, I feel that…
Krish NAik: Yes, you can use this approach.
Krish NAik: But, really, this is a costlier approach. Why? Can anybody tell me why this is a costlier approach?
Krish NAik: Why the OpenAI re-ranking is a costlier approach, guys?
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know in the chat why the OpenAI… because this is an LLM re-ranker-based approach that we are teaching.
Krish NAik: Because if you're passing 20 chunks, okay, 20 chunks sent to 500, let's take.
Krish NAik: How much? 20 into 500?
Krish NAik: So, simply, can I say that directly in one shot, if I am taking in two? 10,000 tokens that I am passing?
Krish NAik: I'm taking a rough number 20 for now, Nagesh.
Krish NAik: Because this number can be changed by, no.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm always, like, 10,000 token. I feel that… Costly.
Krish NAik: Because this… If I… this is 10,000. If I add one zero, How much it will be.
Krish NAik: 1 lakh, if I add one more zero, How much it will be.
Krish NAik: You reached 1 million token, can I say?
Krish NAik: So, can I say that simply for 100 cogs?
Krish NAik: If I make 100 calls, directly I'm reaching that 1 million.
Krish NAik: So, this is a little bit costly operation.
Krish NAik: That's why don't use it.
Krish NAik: Evolution.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, then…
Krish NAik: This is a generic implementation, so here I am actually calling the API, because this is pretty much an API-based approach with the model selection. Okay, so pretty much simple-based approach, where you simply pass on the candidates, and based on that, you get the result type. And if you look into, here.
Krish NAik: I'm just showing you the actual payload that is being sent here. So here, read the relevance of the following document to the query on a scale of 1 to 10.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, dev score only, text using a candidate, get text, candidate.getImageBaseWase64. So, I'm passing what?
Krish NAik: the Base64 modality.
Krish NAik: So, with every chunk, if you have the Base64, that is also being sent to a multimodal. Now, that cost, again, that is also a much…
Krish NAik: Higher cost. I previously had taken only the text, but base 64, that is also a costly operation.
Krish NAik: Now, similarly here also, these are all
Krish NAik: visual re-ranker, so every time I have tried to use the image also.
Krish NAik: So here, also, if you look into, I'm checking the original text, the image base 64, and similarly, based on that, I'm getting the modality.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if modality is equal to image and documents.
Krish NAik: both the things, and that particular payload, I am actually passing it. You can see in the final set of documents.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I'm just making a call through the HTTPS package. This is much better optimized, I can say. Okay, and from there, I'm getting the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a GINA re-ranker, the BG one, really, this re-ranking, we have used it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so fly embedding you can use, and you can install the fast embedding package also, the fast embed package that comes around. So you'll be able to install doc parserBG,
Krish NAik: So, I'm using purely, torch to load up the model, because you need to load up the model into the memory, then only you can do the re-ranking. So, then initializing our re-ranking main function, you are passing the list of candidates, and based on that, you are passing the query and
Krish NAik: list of candidate pairs, and from that, you are applying a scoring, the final re-ranking score for each candidate that will be, thrown to you, and finally, you are doing your sorting operation. This is pretty much a scratch implementation of re-ranking that I've done.
Krish NAik: Because otherwise, every API will do it for you.
Krish NAik: Now comes your, the Quinn BL ranker. I think this, I have used it in the Quinn branch.
Krish NAik: Yeah, because it needs at least 8 to 12 GB of RAM. Okay, so even in your Apple Silicon.
Krish NAik: Okay. It can consume the image Base64 directly, because it can look… pixel by pixel support is there.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here, how to load it up. So here, guys, I have kept it in this way.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, see, guys, now here I am using transformers.
Krish NAik: Okay, for the VL re-ranker, but for the original
Krish NAik: QUIN3, LLM model, what I have used in the Quinn branch.
Krish NAik: What was the serving mechanism?
Krish NAik: Which framework was used for serving?
Krish NAik: Correct, Nagish.
Krish NAik: Please, guys, let me know which framework we used for serving the QNLLM.
Krish NAik: VLLM was the package, it was running in a separate container.
Krish NAik: Anybody remembers that?
Krish NAik: A separate container was there for VLLM.
Krish NAik: All right, fine. If you don't remember, again, please have a look into that. Okay, so here, very specifically for my local running, I have selected, like, self.device. Okay, LCPU, as simple as that. If you don't have a GPU, otherwise you can keep a condition, okay, based on that, LCPU or that.
Krish NAik: Anderson, I think next month it will be.
Krish NAik: Alright, so logger.invoke, loading the quain VL model into the local, okay, and finally check. Now, this particular
Krish NAik: part, I have updated it in the Quinn branch, where actually I am running it in CUDA, and not in MPBS.
Krish NAik: So, score one thing. So, scoring a single query candidate synchronously, in that case, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: And, another is the simple re-rank function, where you can do the re-ranking for all the candidates in one shot.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can say that VLLM till now, or SIGLAN doesn't support
Krish NAik: Re-ranking models. They only support LLMs for him. But that is, I feel that the support for re-rankers and embedding models will come soon. Force are being there. Not all embedding models, I can say, are neither re-ranking model. It is possible to run it through BL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here, the final, this is a factory adapter pattern that we have taken it. So, these are the total backends, get the rack, okay, and based on the base relancer setting from our main ENV file, that will be used then.
Krish NAik: Alright, the core implementation is done here.
Krish NAik: Now, I think, we will start with…
Krish NAik: I think, finally, only we have the routes, so these are all the pedantic schemas. Okay, so did it? All the schemas are available here, you can have a go-through. Middleware logging, that particular thing already I have shown you.
Krish NAik: These are the LRU cache implementations of your few best settings during every API call.
Krish NAik: Alright, now comes your app.py. Now, this is your main entry point of the application from your core FastAPI application start. So, here we are, first of all, getting our generate route, health route, ingest route. So, I think portal, we had 4 routes.
Krish NAik: Based on that, 4 routes, we are importing it, which is inside the routes folder.
Krish NAik: So, we are getting our default settings, setting up our logging settings.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here we are setting up our async Context Manager. We are starting up our application. If anything fails inside that, simply we will say that, shutting down the document parser API. Now here, we are creating the FastAPI application, Zeb, create app, the written type is the FastAPI class type.
Krish NAik: App is equal to FastAPI, class, and here, title, description, version. App.middleware, I'm passing the logging middleware here directly. And there, the core tab. So here, I've said, so these are the prefix routes.
Krish NAik: So, slash injects, slash search, slash generate, and finally the app will be returned, okay? And once this is done, we are simply
Krish NAik: Calling this particular function createApp is equal to create app, and API created successfully.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the final UVicon startup of the application that we have.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, now I think this is the core part with respect to the discussion. Now, I feel that a lot of things are there that, you can change with respect to image captioning part. You can play with these modules, and you can test it up.
Krish NAik: much more. And at least, try to use the ULAMA support with the local GLM CR for now. Otherwise, the written type of the JSO will change. Because of that, the… a lot of things that you need to change it in your chunking part of.
Krish NAik: Because those, needs to be mapped.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you are changing the OCR, that mapping also needs to be changed.
Krish NAik: I think, core things I've already discussed there. Okay, so Anderson is asking, whenever… I think your next task will be next month.
Krish NAik: This month, we will start with the Langra Foundations, and then the fifth project, again, it will take two to three weeks at least.
Krish NAik: Because there, I'm adding EKs also. So, yes, that will be taking more time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you guys can let me know. I can ask a few questions. If anybody has any questions, they can simply raise your hand.
Krish NAik: Let's take some questions. Nagesh, you have raised your hand. Nagesh?
Krish NAik: Alright, there are things and audition orders once on the side.
Krish NAik: Okay, sorry by mistake, alright, no issues.
Krish NAik: So, guys, I think,
Krish NAik: Tomorrow… today it's already 1220. Tomorrow, little bit about the deployment files, the Docker files, the Docker Compose, and then we will start with Langraph tomorrow. Okay?
Krish NAik: I think, Langra.
Krish NAik: Is there any syllabus? I think we will start with language. At least the core fundamentals part.
Krish NAik: What is tool, what is node, what is edge?
Krish NAik: Those type of things will be discussed.
Krish NAik: Okay, next week, then, a little bit more examples.
Krish NAik: with respect to some RAG examples that we have already learned, where I really don't need to focus on the, like, what is CRAG, SELPRAG. Directly, I can take the language-based implementations and show you that.
Krish NAik: So I think that will be better. And then I think,
Krish NAik: We will start with Project 4, I think, next month only, it will be.
Krish NAik: So next one, not Project 4th or Project 5, the final project that will be held.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Rajat, you have raised your hand. Yes, you're in my panelists already. Any questions?
Rajat Khanna: Yes, Paul. So as you were explaining, like, uploading the documents and all, so I asked the question, like, if we can… like, from the front-end side, I have worked on… so, basically, from the front-end only, we convert the uploaded files, for example, Word files, Excel, or the images into Base64. So, how performance is getting approved if the Base64 is not done from the backend?
Rajat Khanna: And it's already done from the front-end side.
Krish NAik: The chunking will be done in the backend only, no?
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes. No, the…
Krish NAik: Parsing part, if you're asking about the parsing part.
Krish NAik: Because, see.
Krish NAik: my parser will tell me the coordinates. Once I have the coordinates, then I can make the crop. Once I can make the crop, then only I can generate the B62.
Rajat Khanna: No, basic… okay, okay, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: How the front-end guy, then the front… see, in the front-end, it means that you will be having the bounding box coordinates from the, GLM OCR output.
Krish NAik: Now, it's here using a simple JavaScript function, wherever there will be an image or a figure tab, that you can directly do the conversion. But, again, in the front end, you need a JavaScript function for it.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes, yeah. Okay, and the other question is related to, like, multiple users accessing our code. So, like, those changes are mainly done on the pod level, pod as in, like, when we deploy our…
Krish NAik: Nobody… multiple users getting access, it means… are you talking about RBAC?
Rajat Khanna: No.
Rajat Khanna: Like, like, same as in, live application, where, like, hundreds or thousands of users interacting with our code base, simultaneously, and we will be running, like, this, GPU model, like, the GPU is getting included. So, how those concurrencies are being handled?
Rajat Khanna: Like, majorly, like, I thought, like, it is not majorly into, like, normally we handle, like, async function calls, caching, and all those things.
Rajat Khanna: But I think majorly those things are done on the deployment aspect of it, like multiple pods are being created, and the load balancing that is happening. So that is not a Python level, that is a production deployment level, if I'm not wrong.
Krish NAik: In, like, when you're asking about 100 users, other things that first thing will come, or back will come into the system, rule-based, where for every user you'll be generating
Krish NAik: a unique bear token. With that Beret token, he will be only hitting, your server. So in that way, you do a lot of restrictions in the final broad level.
Krish NAik: If you want, I can work on a sample demo. You can explore that, I can push it together. Because a lot of things from security perspective, that comes at every point. You need to maintain those things, right?
Krish NAik: Because here, you can use your FastAPI application with 32 workers as working on a multi-instance level. Let's take that you are working on an ECS.
Krish NAik: And I know that multiple containers can spin up at any point of time. So, at least for 100 hits, I'm telling that, okay, now this particular container, after 100 hits, another new container that needs to be spinned up. Now, those are different things at deployment level that need.
Krish NAik: Who handled.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, so my question was basically on those things handled on the Python code, like, fast API level, or in the production level?
Krish NAik: No, I will handle it through in server, probably.
Rajat Khanna: They're relevant.
Krish NAik: Yes, through the engine, it's, probably, I think it will be better.
Krish NAik: Rather than fast API, Boom, put a lot of pressure on Fast API.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, like, Kubernetes, in general, like, we use Kubernetes.
Krish NAik: When it is for orchestration. Okay.
Krish NAik: at container level, or through an engineering side to handle.
Krish NAik: The core rerouting or through a load balancer in that.
Rajat Khanna: So we need to learn those aspects as well.
Krish NAik: everything you have to learn. See, now it's your job role. Are you required to know everything. It totally depends upon the job. Nobody can say that everything, nobody can.
Krish NAik: You just can't explore a certain context of a certain project. The entire project cannot be delivered via single.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, that… thank you, that's it.
Krish NAik: Nothing any more questions? I think more questions. All right, guys, so tomorrow, a little bit about the deployment files I'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: the Gita workflows, CICD, YML files are there, the Docker file is there, the Docker Compose file is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few things were the core changes in the twin branch that I had, that also I'll be discussing, and then we will start with Langra. So, the first part of the class will be a little bit about those deployment files, and then we will start with the Langra fundamentals tool.
Krish NAik: Viraj, you're asking, add human in the loop.
Krish NAik: in the…
Krish NAik: project part C, every time using memory is not my priority. I've used Postgres, but the purpose of using Postgres is different, whereas there.
Krish NAik: Okay, for my long-term memory, I can use that, but I've not added it there. For memory, I have taken a different approach. I'll be showing you in that approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, but a human in the loop is here, so don't worry.
Krish NAik: Initially, let's cover the fundamentals this week. I think the next class, we can discuss more about that.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys, so I think for today, then, we are done. Let's,
Krish NAik: continue the discussion, because the core logic is done, only the deployment files, Docker Compose, and those things are remaining. So I think tomorrow it will be completed, and Landcraft's fundamentals will start tomorrow.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so I think we're good to go. So, bye-bye everyone, thanks for joining. Let's speak tomorrow and continue my discussion.
Krish NAik: really, like, this project for, I think it took around 1 month.
Krish NAik: Just because working on different branches. But I hope it was a good learning experience, working with cheap links and other things for you guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, Project 4, entirely I'm not developed, trying to reduce fee complexities.
Krish NAik: But, let's see, I think by next week, the project will be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, yes, bye-bye. Thanks, everyone.